<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle>A blog by ldstephens.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/" />
  <updated>2025-02-24T17:33:15Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>ldstephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Launch Mac apps with keyboard shortcuts | Keyboard Maestro</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-keyboard-maestro/" />
    <updated>2022-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-keyboard-maestro/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;24 Feb, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning as I sat down at my iMac to start my day, the first thing I did was launch &lt;a href=&quot;https://culturedcode.com/things/&quot;&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ulysses.app/&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt;, and Safari. I do this using keyboard shortcuts. While doing this, it occurred to me that this isn’t the way most people launch apps on their Mac, so I want to share how I do this with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using keyboard shortcuts lets you perform actions faster and more efficiently, cutting down on mouse and trackpad usage. So, how do I create these keyboard shortcuts? I do it using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt;. Within Keyboard Maestro I have a Group called Launch Apps. This is where all my launcher macros live. Here’s the launcher macro, which you can duplicate:&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/MM6uVOx.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;Repeat this for all the apps that you would like to launch using a keyboard shortcut. If you create the macro the way I have, the hotkey will show and hide the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’ll walk you through how to launch apps with keyboard shortcuts using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Launch Mac apps with keyboard shortcuts using Alfred</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-using-alfred/" />
    <updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-using-alfred/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;25 Feb, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-keyboard-maestro&quot;&gt;I wrote&lt;/a&gt; about launching Mac apps with keyboard shortcuts using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; user, you can do the same thing with an Alfred workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, here’s my workflow to launch Safari with the hotkey ⌥S. You’ll need the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/powerpack/&quot;&gt;PowerPack&lt;/a&gt; to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one is to create a new blank workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/jAeGdksC.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step two is to set up a hotkey trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/8IjBw1sU.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step three is adding the Launch Apps action and dragging in the application(s) you want to open. The easiest way to do this is to search for the application or file in Alfred and drag it directly from Alfred&#39;s results into the action box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/qdTFSCgb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/yCyio0EF.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, check the &amp;quot;Toggle visibility for apps&amp;quot; to tell Alfred to show and hide the app. Connect the action to the hotkey to quickly launch the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using keyboard shortcuts lets you perform actions faster and more efficiently, cutting down on mouse and trackpad usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next day or two, I’ll show you how to do this in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/&quot;&gt;Raycast&lt;/a&gt;. It’s super simple. So download it today and in a couple of days, you’ll be launching apps with keyboard shortcuts. Remember it’s FREE.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Launch Mac apps with keyboard shortcuts using Raycast</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-using-raycast/" />
    <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-using-raycast/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;28 Feb, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve written about launching Mac apps with keyboard shortcuts using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-keyboard-maestro&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/launch-mac-apps-with-keyboard-shortcuts-using-alfred&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; now here’s how to do it using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/&quot;&gt;Raycast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First launch Raycast (I use ⌥ spacebar). In the entry field type Extensions then select Applications from the Extensions list and for this example select Safari. Under the Hotkey tab, you’ll see Record Hotkey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/AmmhHoRk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the Safari Hotkey field and Record your keyboard shortcut. I used ⌥ S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/pkY3YFZd.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! From now typing ⌥ S will launch Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using keyboard shortcuts lets you perform actions faster and more efficiently, cutting down on mouse and trackpad usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you’re not using Alfred you should be using Raycast. It does almost everything that Alfred does and it’s FREE.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fastmail vs ProtonMail - A Comparison</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/fastmail-vs-protonmail-a-comparison/" />
    <updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/fastmail-vs-protonmail-a-comparison/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;24 Mar, 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re searching for a private alternative to Google’s Gmail, you need to read this. I started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; when I stopped using Gmail in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fastmail.blog/privacy-security/fastmail-vs-protonmail/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail Blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for a private email service? We break down the similarities and differences between Fastmail and Protonmail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​[…]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastmail, however, provides more of the features users expect from an email service, including an easy-to-use calendar and a powerful search function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another huge difference that sets Fastmail apart is that it offers users the ability to create hundreds of aliases. This allows you to decide which email address is used for what. This increases the level of privacy and puts more control in your hands. Also, Fastmail’s customer service and support are quick to respond, friendly, and are email experts happy to apply their knowledge to your situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​If you&#39;re looking to upgrade your privacy and productivity and join the best in email, go sign up for your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/signup/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;free 30-day trial of Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick Tip - How to delete individual clipboard items from Alfred&#39;s clipboard history</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/quick-tip-how-to-delete-individual-clipboard-items-from-alfreds-clipboard/" />
    <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/quick-tip-how-to-delete-individual-clipboard-items-from-alfreds-clipboard/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 6, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; is the most used app on my Mac. Over the years I&#39;ve written several articles about how I use it &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.net/?s=alfred&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Alfred&#39;s built-in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/help/features/clipboard/&quot;&gt;Clipboard History&lt;/a&gt; and occasionally I want to delete a specific clipboard item. I couldn&#39;t figure out how to do it or if I even could. I googled for an answer and found that Fn + Backspace will delete individual items. Okay, where and the hell is the Backspace key on a Mac keyboard? I&#39;m sure that 99.9% of you probably already know the answer but I didn&#39;t. The Backspace key on a Mac is the Delete key. So to delete an individual clipboard history item in Alfred you use Fn + Backspace (delete key).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this post will be helpful for another Alfred user.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick tip – Add Apps or Folders to the Mac Apple Mail Save As Menu</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/quick-tip-add-apps-or-folders-to-the-mac-apple-mail-save-as-menu/" />
    <updated>2023-02-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/quick-tip-add-apps-or-folders-to-the-mac-apple-mail-save-as-menu/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&#39;t aware of this feature and I&#39;m guessing I&#39;m not the only one so I thought I’d share how to add items to the Mac Apple Mail “Save as” menu. I’ve added GoodNotes, My Inbox, Apple Notes, and DEVONthink to this menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/jgNsozh8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s how you do it, Select “Print” (Cmd+P) and then, “Edit Menu” and then add or delete apps or folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.macpowerusers.com/t/how-to-add-apps-to-the-apple-mail-save-as-menu/32573&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Fake a Dropped Call on iPhone</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-fake-a-dropped-call-on-iphone/" />
    <updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-fake-a-dropped-call-on-iphone/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 12, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bet you&#39;ve been on a phone call you wanted to end and couldn&#39;t come up with a way to do it. A dropped call is the perfect solution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can simulate a dropped call on an iPhone by turning on Airplane Mode. This can be done through Control Center by swiping down from the top right corner of the display and tapping on the Airplane icon or through the Settings app by toggling the Airplane Mode switch. The Airplane Mode disconnects all cellular and network connections on your iPhone and results in an active call being dropped even though the reason for the drop was initiated by the user and not by poor service or network issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just learned &lt;a href=&quot;https://osxdaily.com/2023/02/08/how-fake-drop-call-iphone/&quot;&gt;this little trick&lt;/a&gt; the other day and I thought I would share it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>7 Reasons why I register domains with Hover</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/7-reasons-why-i-register-domains-with-hover/" />
    <updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/7-reasons-why-i-register-domains-with-hover/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 23, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years of using GoDaddy, I registered my first domain with&lt;a href=&quot;https://hover.com/uVPu2FkM&quot;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; in 2016. By the way, I&#39;m pretty sure I heard about Hover on an MPU podcast years ago. Anyway, having my domains with Hover has been an unbelievably good experience. Here&#39;s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple domain management experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hundreds of domain extensions to choose from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free Whois Privacy to protect my contact information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powerful domain management tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No upselling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No spam. Hover only sends me a reminder when my domains are about to expire. That&#39;s it. No unwanted emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone, chat, and email support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for a better domain registration service to register your domains, don&#39;t hesitate. Register your next domain with Hover. And please use my &lt;a href=&quot;https://hover.com/uVPu2FkM&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; so I get credit. This helps support this blog and costs you nothing extra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: I&#39;d still recommend them even if they didn&#39;t have an affiliate program.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Restart your iPhone using Siri</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/restart-your-iphone-using-siri/" />
    <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/restart-your-iphone-using-siri/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 24, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to restart your iPhone for any reason, such as to fix a glitch or to clear out the memory, there are several ways to do it. The easiest way is to restart your iPhone is by using Siri. Here&#39;s how to do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activate Siri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say Restart my iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siri will confirm that you want to restart your iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say Yes to confirm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siri will initiate the restart process, and your iPhone will turn off and then turn back on again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can restart your iPhone the normal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press and hold either volume button and the side button until the power-off slider appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swipe the slider to the right to turn off your iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once your iPhone is turned off, press and hold the side button again until the Apple logo appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your iPhone will start up as normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, I wasn&#39;t aware that it&#39;s possible to restart my iPhone using Siri. I suspect that there may be others who are also unaware of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When the Internet Goes Dark</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-the-internet-goes-dark/" />
    <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-the-internet-goes-dark/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about this a lot lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture this: you wake up one day, pour yourself a cup of coffee, and sit down at your computer, ready to start your day. But as soon as you try to load up your favorite website, you&#39;re met with an error message. You try a few more sites, but nothing seems to be working. Suddenly, it hits you – the internet is down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it might not seem like a big deal. You&#39;ll just have to find something else to do with your time for a little while, right? Wrong. It&#39;s a massive, extended internet outage, which will result in severe implications for our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, communication would be severely impacted. You wouldn&#39;t be able to send emails, use social media, or even video chat with your loved ones. Imagine having to resort to snail mail or – gasp! – actually talking on the phone to keep in touch with people. Oops! Who even has a fucking landline phone these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many companies relying on the internet to conduct their operations, a prolonged outage could cause chaos and confusion. Online retailers, banks, and stock markets would all take a major hit. Can you even imagine the chaos that would ensue if people couldn&#39;t access their online bank accounts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let&#39;s not forget about entertainment. The internet has revolutionized the way we entertain ourselves. Streaming videos and music online, playing games, and browsing social media have all become staples of our daily lives. Without the internet, we&#39;d have to resort to other forms of entertainment – maybe even (gasp!) reading a book or going outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to information would also be severely limited. The internet has made it easy to access vast amounts of information with just a few clicks. But without it, we&#39;d have to rely on old-fashioned methods like books, newspapers, and TV news (cable only streamers are shit out of luck).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long-term internet outage would be no joke. It would completely upend our way of life and force us to adapt to a world without constant connectivity. So the next time you&#39;re cursing your internet provider for a shitty connection, just remember it could be worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ldstephens Blog - Eight Years of Blogging and Counting</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-blog-eight-years-of-blogging-and-counting/" />
    <updated>2023-03-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-blog-eight-years-of-blogging-and-counting/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 14, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my walk the other day I was listening to John Gruber&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+B7NBTeKaY&quot;&gt;The Talk Show podcast&lt;/a&gt;. His guest was Jason Kottke who is celebrating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kottke.org/23/03/kottke-is-25-years-old-today&quot;&gt;25th anniversary&lt;/a&gt; of his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John and Jason reminisced about the history of their blogs as well as the history of blogging in general. As I was listening I started thinking about my history of writing a blog and it goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of my blog is simply ldstephens. The first two letters are my first and middle initials and then my last name. I choose this because the domain Stephens wasn&#39;t available so I picked an available variation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I decided to start a blog I knew that I wanted to blog about technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I published my very first blog post on Medium in September 2015. In August of 2016, I decided to start blogging as ldstephens and moved to WordPress so that I could have my domain (ldstephens.net), identity, and place on the web. At this point, I cross-posted most of my posts to Medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021 I wanted to move away from WordPress and the block editor. I disliked the block editor because it took time to learn and get used to compared to the classic editor. It slowed down my editing process. I like writing content in markdown in one place and then posting it to WordPress, which is contrary to the block editor&#39;s “block” approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in 2021, I decided it was time to leave the WordPress platform. After a fair amount of research on blogging platforms, I settled on write.as. I wanted to keep the ldstephens name and settled on the domain ldstephens.me. I published my first post here in December 2021 and I&#39;m very happy here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said I&#39;ve been doing this going on 8 years. I love doing it and plan to be doing it for as long as I can type on a keyboard. I don&#39;t have a huge audience but the one that I do has been loyal and I thank you all for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Benefits of Personal Blogs Over Social Media Platforms</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-benefits-of-personal-blogs-over-social-media-platforms/" />
    <updated>2023-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-benefits-of-personal-blogs-over-social-media-platforms/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 25, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never been a big fan of social media platforms. In fact, I&#39;ve never had a Facebook account. I tried Instagram when it was first introduced but canceled it shortly thereafter since I&#39;m not a photography buff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had a Twitter account off and on since its inception. But honestly, I never found much value in it other than promoting my blog posts. Thanks to the shithead that now owns Twitter, I recently deleted my account again. Against my better judgment I just this week signed up for a new account only to promote my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reluctant to sign up for a Mastodon account but I finally caved in a little over a month ago. Like Twitter I don&#39;t find much value in Mastodon so for now I&#39;m going to keep my account but I won&#39;t be active other than to promote my blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I find far better than social media are personal blogs. There are several benefits to following personal blogs rather than relying on social media platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authenticity: Personal blogs are often more authentic than social media posts. Bloggers write longer posts and share more detailed stories about their lives or topics that interest them, allowing me to get a better sense of who they are as individuals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community: Many personal blogs have a strong community of readers and followers who engage with the blogger and each other. This creates a sense of belonging and connection that may not be as strong on social media platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longevity: Blog posts are usually archived and can be accessed at any time, whereas social media posts are often fleeting and get buried in a user&#39;s feed within hours or days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, personal blogs provide me with a personalized, in-depth, and authentic experience that social media doesn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reading, linking, writing, and blogging</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/reading-linking-writing-and-blogging/" />
    <updated>2023-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/reading-linking-writing-and-blogging/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 10, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who spends a considerable amount of time consuming and sharing information on the web, I understand the importance of optimizing the process. Fortunately, through the use of right tools and workflows, I have been able to streamline this process. So I thought I would share it with you today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My workflow consists of the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading&lt;/strong&gt;: I Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds with &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedbin.com/&quot;&gt;Feedbin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reederapp.com/&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt;. Goodlinks is for reading-later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linking&lt;/strong&gt;: Once I am ready to start capturing ideas and writing, I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful app that allows me to quickly capture my thoughts and ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;: Drafts is where I write and publish shorter posts, and for longer pieces, I export my ideas to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ia.net/writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;. iA Writer lets me better organize and structure my content before publishing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using these tools and workflows, I have been able to reduce the time and effort it takes to stay informed and share information with you my faithful readers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>FBI warns against using public phone charging stations</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/fbi-warns-against-using-public-phone-charging-stations/" />
    <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/fbi-warns-against-using-public-phone-charging-stations/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know my readers are probably already aware of this, but I&#39;ll mention it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2023/04/10/fbi-says-you-shouldnt-use-public-phone-charging-stations.html&quot;&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FBI recently warned consumers against using free public charging stations, saying crooks have managed to hijack public chargers that can infect devices with malware, or software that can give hackers access to your phone, tablet or computer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avoid using free charging stations in airports, hotels or shopping centers,” a tweet from the FBI’s Denver field office said. “Bad actors have figured out ways to use public USB ports to introduce malware and monitoring software onto devices. Carry your own charger and USB cord and use an electrical outlet instead.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FBI has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/safety-resources/scams-and-safety/on-the-internet&quot;&gt;similar warning&lt;/a&gt; on its website against using public WiFi for sensitive transactions, opening suspicious documents, using the same password for all accounts, and clicking unsolicited links in text messages and emails.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Making Computers Personal</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/making-computers-personal/" />
    <updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/making-computers-personal/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 19, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wormsandviruses.com/2023/04/making-computers-personal/&quot;&gt;Jack Wellborn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal automation doesn’t need to involve expensive third party hardware, or require scripting. It can be something as as simple as &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/mac-help/create-keyboard-shortcuts-for-apps-mchlp2271/mac&quot;&gt;customizing keyboard shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; or defining &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/mac-help/replace-text-punctuation-documents-mac-mh35735/mac&quot;&gt;text replacement&lt;/a&gt; macros. Apple’s Shortcuts app is completely drag-and-drop, and makes building personal automation easy enough for even basic users. On top of the many automation apps and&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/mac-help/create-or-change-a-smart-folder-on-mac-mchlp2804/mac&quot;&gt;features&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/mac-help/turn-a-focus-on-or-off-mchl999b7c1a/mac&quot;&gt;included&lt;/a&gt; with Apple’s platforms, there are also a slew of great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;third&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noodlesoft.com/&quot;&gt;party&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://textexpander.com/&quot;&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; that unlock even more possibilities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal computers have become easier and more accessible, to the point where they and their apps are necessarily built for everyone. That’s truly great, but being easy and more accessible doesn’t make them personal. It makes them general purpose. Personal automation gives individuals the power to make their general purpose computer that was built for everyone actually personal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using apps such as Drafts, Raycast, Keyboard Maestro, PopClip, and Hazel, I have customized my Mac with a significant amount of automation. As a result, using another person’s Mac feels unfamiliar to me. That’s how feel when my wife asks me to help her out with something on her Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remembering Nemo - a tribute to our beloved dog</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/remembering-nemo-a-tribute-to-our-beloved-dog/" />
    <updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/remembering-nemo-a-tribute-to-our-beloved-dog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 19, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/hfEejt81.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/2f17j56r.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the ninth anniversary of our dog Nemo’s passing. Nemo was an amazing dog who enriched our lives in so many ways. When we first adopted him, we were told that he had been at the shelter for about a year and had been adopted a few times and returned. It was clear that Nemo was meant to be with us, and I’m so grateful that I got to be his human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2013, I noticed that Nemo was having trouble with his balance when he lifted his leg to pee. He eventually lost his balance and would fall over, so I took him to the vet. He was diagnosed with degenerative myelopathy, a terrible disease that slowly degenerates the spinal cord. Nemo’s condition worsened over time, and it was heartbreaking to see him lose his muscle strength, stumble, and eventually become incontinent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2014, we made the difficult decision to let Nemo go. It was a painful decision, but we knew that it was the right thing to do for our beloved dog. With vet assistance, Nemo passed away on Saturday, April 19th, 2014. I still fucking miss him every day, but we take comfort in knowing that he is in a better place now, running and playing with Tonka and Lola.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Three to One</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/from-three-to-one/" />
    <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/from-three-to-one/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 27, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/&quot;&gt;Raycast&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; for productivity and automation. Today it occurred to me that this is fucking silly! Why use three apps when I can do it all with one? With Alfred&#39;s built-in Features and 16 Workflows, I can do everything that I was doing in three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t get me wrong, Keyboard Maestro and Raycast are both wonderful apps. Buy I&#39;ve realized that I don&#39;t need them any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/blog&quot;&gt;Back to Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Everyday Essentials - Alfred, Drafts, and PopClip – The Backbone of My Workflow</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-everyday-essentials-alfred-drafts-and-popclip-the-backbone-of/" />
    <updated>2023-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-everyday-essentials-alfred-drafts-and-popclip-the-backbone-of/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I want to introduce you to three essential Mac apps: Alfred, Drafts, and PopClip. These apps have become the backbone of my daily routine, enabling me to navigate, capture, and process information with remarkable efficiency. Let’s delve into each app’s unique features and see how they can transform your workflow too. Alfred’s versatility and customization options make it an indispensable tool for boosting productivity and streamlining your daily workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drafts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Get Drafts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts is an ingenious note-taking app designed to capture and process your thoughts, ideas and more effortlessly. Its primary strength lies in its ability to quickly capture text from anywhere on your Mac and provide a range of actions to manipulate that text. Drafts excels in turning your ideas into actions, making it an excellent companion for writers, thinkers, and anyone in need of a reliable digital scratchpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick note capture: Launch Drafts, jot down your thoughts, and it automatically saves your notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actions: Transform your notes with a variety of powerful actions, including sending to other apps, formatting, creating tasks, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation: Utilize scripts and integrations to automate your workflow and send your notes to multiple destinations simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts’ simplicity, coupled with its powerful features and customizable actions, makes it an invaluable tool for capturing and processing ideas efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PopClip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pilotmoon.com/popclip/&quot;&gt;Get PopClip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PopClip is a clever utility that enhances your text-editing capabilities by providing a handy popover menu with relevant actions whenever you select text. With PopClip, you can quickly perform actions like copying, pasting, searching, formatting, and sharing, without having to navigate through menus or remember keyboard shortcuts. It’s a small yet incredibly convenient app that significantly boosts your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contextual actions: PopClip displays a customizable set of actions whenever you select text, allowing you to perform common tasks effortlessly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customization: Tailor the available actions to your specific needs by adding or removing extensions from a growing library of options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clipboard history: PopClip keeps track of your copied text, enabling you to access previously copied content easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PopClip’s unobtrusive nature and seamless integration into your existing workflow make it an essential utility for anyone who deals with text on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the right tools can make a world of difference in your productivity. Alfred, Drafts, and PopClip have become integral parts of my workflow, enabling me to work smarter and accomplish more in less time. By seamlessly integrating into your daily routine, these apps empower you to streamline tasks, capture and process information effortlessly, and enhance your overall productivity. Give them a try and experience the transformative power they bring to your Mac experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Easy Link Opening in iPadOS</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/easy-link-opening-in-ipados/" />
    <updated>2023-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/easy-link-opening-in-ipados/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 13, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered the “Open Link” option in the iPadOS right-click menu. When working in a text editor on iPadOS or iOS, I often deal with both words and links. Sometimes, I want to open one of those links in Safari. However, in a text editor, links aren&#39;t clickable for direct opening. What I discovered is that in iPadOS 16 and iOS 16, if you select a link and right-click on it, the menu now includes an “Open Link” option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/HLqk7RdS.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume you might already be aware of this feature, but for me, it was a new discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Convert Photos to PDF on iPhone and iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-convert-photos-to-pdf-on-iphone-and-ipad/" />
    <updated>2023-06-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-convert-photos-to-pdf-on-iphone-and-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 23, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, there are times when you may want to convert an image to a PDF. There are several reasons why you might want to do this. Firstly, PDFs are easily shareable; you can send them via email, text message, or upload them online. Secondly, PDFs are more secure than image files, which can be easily edited or altered. Converting your photos to PDFs ensures that they remain unchanged. Finally, PDFs take up less space on your device than image files, which can help you free up storage space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Steps to Convert Photos to PDF on iPhone and iPad&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch the Photos app on your iPhone and tap the Select button in the top-right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, tap to select the photos you want to convert to PDF and tap the Share button in the bottom-right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swipe up the Share Sheet to reveal all the options and tap the Print button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will see the print preview of all the selected photos. Tap the Share button in the top-right corner and choose the Save to Files option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, tap the Save button to save the PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To open the PDF file, launch the Files app and navigate to the location you have saved the file. By default, it will be the Downloads folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you can see, we have created the PDF from selected photos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converting your photos to PDF is a simple and effective way to organize and share your images. PDFs are more secure than image files, take up less space on your device, and retain their formatting when opened on any device. With the steps outlined above, you can easily convert your photos to PDF on your iPhone or iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to recover deleted files on iPhone and iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-recover-deleted-files-on-iphone-and-ipad/" />
    <updated>2023-07-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-recover-deleted-files-on-iphone-and-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 3, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you accidentally deleted a file on your iPhone or iPad? It can be super frustrating, especially if the file was important. But don&#39;t worry, it&#39;s super easy to recover deleted files using the Recently Deleted feature in the Files app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Deleted in the Files app is kinda like the Trash on a Mac. When you delete a file, it goes into the Recently Deleted folder where it hangs out for 30 days before being permanently deleted. This gives you a chance to recover the file if you change your mind. When you delete a file, it goes into the Recently Deleted folder where it stays for 30 days before being permanently deleted. This gives you a chance to recover the file if you change your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Files app and tap on “Browse”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap on “Recently Deleted” under “Locations”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap on the deleted file you want to recover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap on “Recover”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to keep in mind is that you only have 30 days to recover a deleted file before it is permanently deleted. If you don&#39;t see the file in the Recently Deleted folder, it may have already been deleted permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losing a file can be a stressful experience, but with the Recently Deleted feature in the Files app, you can recover your deleted files with ease. Just remember to check the Recently Deleted folder within 30 days of deleting the file. By following these simple steps, you&#39;ll never have to worry about losing an important file on your iPhone or iPad again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding iPhone&#39;s orange, green, and blue privacy indicator dots</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/understanding-iphones-orange-green-and-blue-privacy-indicator-dots/" />
    <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/understanding-iphones-orange-green-and-blue-privacy-indicator-dots/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/MhjUI2N4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share a discovery I made this week regarding those seemingly insignificant colored dots near the front-facing camera on your iPhone. These dots, known as Apple status bar icons, serve as warning signals for potential privacy invasions. Understanding their meaning can help protect your online safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newer iPhone models have integrated privacy indicators that activate these dots when accessing certain features. There are three main colored dots to be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orange Dot&lt;/strong&gt;: An orange dot signifies that your device&#39;s microphone is actively being used by an app. This can serve as an alert to potentially unauthorized microphone access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green Dot&lt;/strong&gt;: A green dot, similar in size and shape to the orange dot, indicates that your device&#39;s camera is currently in use by an app. It&#39;s crucial to be cautious if this dot appears unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue Dot with White Arrow&lt;/strong&gt;: The blue dot, featuring a white arrow pointing right, appears when an app is attempting to access your location. This dot should raise concern if you&#39;re not expecting an app to use your location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s important to note that a blue dot appearing alongside apps on your home screen indicates that the app has recently been updated and doesn&#39;t relate to privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify which apps are using your camera, microphone, or location, you can check the App Privacy Report in Settings, which provides a comprehensive log of apps that have used sensitive permissions and when they accessed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding and monitoring these privacy indicator dots can enhance your control over your personal data and safeguard your online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to setup folders in Fastmail that auto-purge emails</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-setup-folders-in-fastmail-that-auto-purge-emails/" />
    <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-setup-folders-in-fastmail-that-auto-purge-emails/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 24, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; has folders that will auto-purge emails? This feature allows you to automatically delete messages from a folder after a certain amount of time. I’ve found that this is a great way to manage notification emails that I want to keep but not forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up a folder with auto-purge, just follow these simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; page in Fastmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Folders&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the folder that you want to set up auto-purge for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down to the &lt;strong&gt;Automated Actions&lt;/strong&gt; section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the box next to &lt;strong&gt;Auto-purge this folder on a selected date&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the number of days after which you want the messages to be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! Once you&#39;ve set up a folder with auto-purge, any messages that are older than the specified number of days will be automatically deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try Fastmail for Free for 30 Days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up for a free trial of Fastmail today and see for yourself why it&#39;s the best email service on the market. With unlimited storage, strong security, and a clean and modern interface, Fastmail is the perfect way to keep your inbox organized and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click here to sign up for a free trial: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;30 Day Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to change font size for individual apps on iPhone and iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-change-font-size-for-individual-apps-on-iphone-and-ipad/" />
    <updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-change-font-size-for-individual-apps-on-iphone-and-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on September 9, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most iPhone and iPad users are familiar with the option to change font size in Mail, Contacts, Calendar, Phone, Notes, and other apps that support Dynamic Type. To do this, simply go to Settings &amp;gt; Display &amp;amp; Brightness, then choose Text Size and use the slider to select your preferred font size. However, many might not know how to adjust font size in an individual app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I encountered a situation where I needed to change the font size in a specific app that utilizes Dynamic Type. I wanted to modify the font size in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodnotes.com/&quot;&gt;Goodnotes&lt;/a&gt; without affecting other apps. It took me a few minutes to recall the process, but you can indeed change font size for individual apps on your iPhone or iPad by following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the app for which you want to change the font size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Control Center by swiping down from the top-right corner of your screen. For iPhones with a Home button, swipe up from the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the Text Size icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the All Apps icon is blue, tap the [This App] Only icon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your finger to move the slider up or down to change the font size for the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more white bars, the larger the font size. Look at the top of the screen for a preview of the actual size of the font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>xSearch A Safari extension for improved searching on iPhone and iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/xsearch-a-safari-extension-for-improved-searching-on-iphone-and-ipad/" />
    <updated>2023-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/xsearch-a-safari-extension-for-improved-searching-on-iphone-and-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on September 10, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, while using my iPad, I often stumble upon new apps that help me be more productive. Take, for example, my Mac setup – I’ve got Alfred triggers that speed up searches on certain websites. These websites usually have a predictable URL structure for search results, making automation pretty easy. With Alfred, you can set up the URL, add your search terms, and boom, you’re searching away. You can kinda do something similar with Shortcuts on iOS and iPadOS, but it’s not as smooth because it doesn’t work directly from the address bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/xsearch-for-safari/id1579902068&quot;&gt;xSearch&lt;/a&gt;, you can set up the same sort of thing inside the address bar. xSearch is an iOS and iPadOS Safari extension that allows you to seamlessly switch between multiple search engines with ease, and even search directly from Spotlight. This can make your browsing experience more efficient and.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the features of xSearch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch between multiple search engines with ease: You can add as many search engines as you want to xSearch, and then switch between them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search directly from Spotlight: You can also use xSearch to search directly from Spotlight, without having to open Safari first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom search prefixes: You can create custom search prefixes for each search engine. For example, you could set up a prefix of “g” to search Google, and a prefix of “ddg” to search DuckDuckGo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shortcuts: You can also create shortcuts for frequently searched terms. For example, you could create a shortcut for “weather” that would search for the weather in your current location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xSearch is a paid app on the App Store, priced at only $1.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this app boosts your iPhone and iPad productivity!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Mail&#39;s missing Snooze - Setting the record straight</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-mails-missing-snooze-setting-the-record-straight/" />
    <updated>2023-09-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-mails-missing-snooze-setting-the-record-straight/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on September 26, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, Apple’s built-in Mail app has become pretty feature complete over the years. Though the latest email features take a year or two to show up in Mail, most have made their way into the app — features like Send Later, Snooze, Undo Send, and more are now all in Apple’s default Mail app and available to all iPhone, iPad, and Mac users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Apple Mail but I want to point out one misleading statement in this paragraph. Apple Mail does not have snooze! It&#39;s a feature that I wish it had. It does have Remind Me Later which is very different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snoozed email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moves the email to a Snooze folder until the specified time. ￼The email is still visible in the Snooze folder, so you can easily find it and take action if needed. ￼If someone replies to a snoozed email, it will be un-snoozed and moved back to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remind Me Later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creates a reminder for the email, but the email remains in your inbox. You can set a specific date and time for the reminder, or you can choose to be reminded at a later time, such as when you arrive at a specific location or when you complete another task. If someone replies to a reminded email, the reminder will remain active, but the email will be moved to the top of your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find Remind Me Later to be useless.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bartender to Hidden Bar - A Simpler Solution for macOS Sonoma</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/bartender-to-hidden-bar-a-simpler-solution-for-macos-sonoma/" />
    <updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/bartender-to-hidden-bar-a-simpler-solution-for-macos-sonoma/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 11, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, friends! I&#39;ve been a long-time user of Mac Bartender, an application for macOS that helps you organize and customize your menu bar, simplifying the management of icons and notifications for a cleaner and more efficient desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With macOS Sonoma, upgrading from Bartender version 4 to the new version 5 is necessary. While I don&#39;t mind paying for the upgrade, each iteration of Bartender adds features that I don&#39;t find necessary, and the same holds true for version 5. So, as I said, I don&#39;t mind the upgrade cost, but the app now offers more features than I actually need. That&#39;s why I&#39;m giving Hidden Bar from Superbits, a simpler solution, a try. In the end, it provides the basic features I need and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://superbits.co/static/5dfd20996f42c6d8cca11335423f8fd5/23b0e/light-and-dark-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Private Relay - It&#39;s not worth the Wi-Fi speed sacrifice</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-private-relay-its-not-worth-the-wi-fi-speed-sacrifice/" />
    <updated>2023-10-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-private-relay-its-not-worth-the-wi-fi-speed-sacrifice/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 26, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I experienced an unexpected Wi-Fi slowdown, so I an investigation. We have Gigabit internet, and our Wi-Fi typically delivers speeds between 750 Mbps and 1000 Mbps. To start, I ran a speed test on my Eero router and received 998 Mbps. That indicated that the issue was between the router and my devices. Next, I conducted speed tests on my MacBook and iPhone, but they were achieving speeds between 150 Mbps and 250 Mbps. I was left wondering, what the fuck could be causing this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some fiddling, I recalled that a few weeks ago, I had enabled Apple Private Relay. It immediately struck me that this might be the culprit. So, I disabled it on all my devices. An not to my surprise, my Wi-Fi speeds returned to normal across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private Relay is a network security feature provided by Apple to its iCloud subscribers. It serves as an iCloud security feature that safeguards your internet browsing history by routing your data through two separate internet relays and encrypting your DNS records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do recognize the value of Apple Private Relay, it&#39;s clear that the throughput needs significant improvement before I&#39;ll consider turning it back on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back to Drafts app as my information repository</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/back-to-drafts-app-as-my-information-repository/" />
    <updated>2023-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/back-to-drafts-app-as-my-information-repository/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 18, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I made a significant decision to move away from using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; as my primary information repository. At the time, I transferred all my notes, research, long-term thinking, and journaling from Drafts to plain text files. It felt like a big shift. However, just this week, I made another change. I moved all my text-processing tasks back into Drafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Drafts is now my go-to for notes, research, long-term thinking, and journaling, I still prefer to do my writing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; versus Drafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, if you&#39;re considering using Drafts as an information repository, remember that it strictly supports plain text only. Rich content like images or videos is a no-go. To fill this gap, I rely on Apple&#39;s Notes app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for my shift back to Drafts is my dissatisfaction with managing individual files in Finder, especially on the Files app for my iPhone and iPad. Drafts is a more powerful and versatile solution. Its database structure provides several advantages, including better organization, robust search capabilities, version control, collaboration features, automation, easy export options, and seamless syncing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate over whether to use individual files or a database for storing information is ongoing. There&#39;s no definitive answer; it simply boils down to personal preference. In my case, the flexibility and features of Drafts won me over once again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>App-solutely indecisive</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/app-solutely-indecisive/" />
    <updated>2023-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/app-solutely-indecisive/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 19, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself constantly switching between different apps, services, and devices, much like I&#39;d change my underwear. Why can&#39;t I just settle on what works best for me and stop this endless cycle of app flip-flopping? What the fuck is up with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My problem is that I&#39;m easily influenced by what other tech enthusiasts are using. If they&#39;re using app X, I feel like I should be using app X too. This tendency is particularly evident in the blogging world, where it&#39;s become a trend to publish blog posts listing the default apps used for various tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaults.rknight.me/&quot;&gt;I browsed through some of these blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, evaluating how many people were using Reeder versus NetNewWire and whether they were using Feedbin or iCloud for their backend. This sparked my interest because &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/renewing-my-feedbin-subscription-a-lingering-dilemma&quot;&gt;my Feedbin subscription is up for renewal&lt;/a&gt; in a few weeks, and I&#39;m considering eliminating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another area that piqued my curiosity was the notes and writing apps that others were using. I was particularly interested in how many people were using Drafts, an app I personally love for all my text-based needs. However, noticing that Drafts wasn&#39;t as popular as I&#39;d expected made me question whether I should switch to Ulysses or iA Writer, which were mentioned more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure you get the gist of my problem. My goal is to finally settle on the apps that genuinely work for me and break free from this endless cycle of app flip-flopping. How about you?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Renewing my Feedbin subscription - A lingering dilemma</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/renewing-my-feedbin-subscription-a-lingering-dilemma/" />
    <updated>2023-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/renewing-my-feedbin-subscription-a-lingering-dilemma/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 19, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedbin.com/&quot;&gt;Feedbin&lt;/a&gt; RSS service subscription is due for renewal in a few weeks, and I&#39;m once again grappling with the decision of whether or not to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I reached a point where I couldn&#39;t tolerate Reeder&#39;s unreliable iCloud sync service any longer. It&#39;s iCloud sync has been plagued with issues since the 5.3.5 or 5.3.6 update, causing me endless frustration. To address this problem, I had two options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to Feedbin, which works seamlessly with Reeder and offers lightning-fast sync. However, this would incur an annual $50 fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to NetNewsWire, where iCloud sync works okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dilemma stems from my preference for Reeder over NetNewsWire. But is the convenience of Reeder worth the $50 annual Feedbin subscription?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I&#39;m facing the same decision yet again. I&#39;ve been testing iCloud sync on both Reeder and NetNewsWire. While Reeder&#39;s sync has improved, it still falls short of my expectations. NetNewsWire, on the other hand, performs okay but lacks the speed of Feedbin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could conceivably adapt to using NetNewsWire and iCloud sync. However, I&#39;ve been a loyal Reeder user since version 3 in 2016, and I genuinely adore the app. With a few weeks left before my decision deadline, I&#39;m leaning towards renewing my Feedbin subscription and sticking with Reeder.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keyboard Maestro Macro - Close all open tabs and hide Safari</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/keyboard-maestro-macro-close-all-open-tabs-and-hide-safari/" />
    <updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/keyboard-maestro-macro-close-all-open-tabs-and-hide-safari/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 20, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the research phase for blog posts, I often end up with numerous tabs open in Safari. Once I&#39;ve finished utilizing these tabs, I&#39;d like to have the option to close them all and hide Safari simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways to close tabs on a Mac. The simplest way is to use the keyboard shortcut Command+W. Alternatively, you can click on the “x” button in the top-left corner of each tab, or you can right-click on the tab and select an option from the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/v2/format:webp/1*y1ITbicOumgT4Xlz8hqEfQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to close all tabs in a window, you can use the keyboard shortcut Command+Option+W. Whatever option you use to close the tabs, Safari is still the active window, and you still have to hide Safari Command+H.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, I want all this to happen simultaneously with a keyboard shortcut, so I created the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; macro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safari Group&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/v2/format:webp/1*tVrNmNMZGLvwJ4k3DCBcHw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macro&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/v2/format:webp/1*JV1qar75Ibma9b9J1AaYXw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I execute the Option+Command+H keyboard shortcut in Safari, it closes all the open tabs and hides Safari. This saves numerous clicks and keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Ad-Blockers</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-ad-blockers/" />
    <updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-ad-blockers/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 20, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/on-ad-blockers&quot;&gt;Manu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter the case, ads on the web will always be tricky and live in this bizarre gray area. And until someone comes up with a really compelling argument for allowing ads I&#39;ll keep running ad-blockers because I just can&#39;t stand ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, web ads, the unsolicited guests that never fucking leave. I have been using an ad-blocker since they were first available to consumers. My blocker of choice for Safari is &lt;a href=&quot;https://kaylees.site/wipr.html&quot;&gt;Wiper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ublockorigin.com/&quot;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; for Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I&#39;m also annoyed by websites that bug me with a popup to sign to receive their email. You know who you are so stop it already.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My default apps – 2024 version</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-default-apps-2024-version/" />
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-default-apps-2024-version/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 14, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, buckle up because I&#39;m diving into the trend sweeping Hemispheric Views and bloggers everywhere. Just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaults.rknight.me/&quot;&gt;over 200 other bloggers&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;m laying out my default apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mac&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;macOS: 14.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail App: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: Things 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud File Storage: iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts / iA Writer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App Launcher: Alfred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS Service: Feedbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS App: Reeder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPN: TunnelBear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilities: Hazel, Keyboard Maestro, PopClip, Yoink, DropZone, App Cleaner, Moom, Witch, Hidden Bar, ScreenFloat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;iPad Pro and Mini&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPadOS: 17.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail App: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Notes / Goodnotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: Things 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts / iA Writer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS Service: Feedbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS App: Reeder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal: Day One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPN: TunnelBear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;iPhone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iOS: 17.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail App: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messages: Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: Things 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS Service: Feedbin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS App: Reeder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal: Day One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Manager: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPN: TunnelBear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather: Carrot Weather / Hello Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and Fitness: Fitness, FoodNoms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I abandoned Drafts and returned to text files for managing my information repository</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/why-i-abandoned-drafts-and-returned-to-text-files-for-managing-my-information/" />
    <updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/why-i-abandoned-drafts-and-returned-to-text-files-for-managing-my-information/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 14, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ldstephens/back-to-drafts-app-as-my-information-repository-1650876c7c72&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed my decision to switch back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;as my primary information repository. While this move has proven beneficial, there was one lingering concern: the potential for data loss due to database corruption or iCloud taking a shit. To address this concern, I adopted the practice of saving all information in both Drafts and text files. However, maintaining synchronization between the database and files has become a constant challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After careful consideration, I concluded that storing information in both Drafts and text files was an unnecessary redundancy. Since I am unwilling to abandon text files, I decided to eliminate Drafts as an information repository and rely solely on text files for data storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement this change, I have consolidated all my text files within the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ia.net/writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt; library. Drafts now serves as a temporary workspace for short-term notes and text capture, with permanent information residing in text files accessible from any text editor. Additionally, I have integrated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houdah.com/houdahSpot/?lang=en&quot;&gt;HoudahSpot&lt;/a&gt; search to facilitate efficient information retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident that this simplified system will serve my information management needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I hated writing with the Apple Pencil on my iPad. Not anymore!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-hated-writing-with-the-apple-pencil-on-my-ipad/" />
    <updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-hated-writing-with-the-apple-pencil-on-my-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 17, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time on my iPads. One thing I would like to do more often is use my Apple Pencil for thinking and jotting down quick notes. But I didn’t because it doesn&#39;t fucking feel right. Paper is paper and pen on paper is something entirely different. What I discovered is that writing with the Pencil on iPad can feel more like pen and paper depending on the tool that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read Thord Hedengren’s article “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bored.horse/post/writing-on-glass/&quot;&gt;Writing on Glass – PenTips&lt;/a&gt;” in line with this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve tried two alternatives recently, and finally feel ready to mention them. Both are from an accessory maker called PenTips and, as the name implies, they focus on custom tips for your Apple Pencil. I actually went for their other option first however, which is a screen protector much like Paperlike and its ilk. […] Being that impressed with PenTips&#39;s magnetic matte screen protectors, I had to try their Apple Pencil tips. They&#39;re available in a wide variety, and sold in packs. That implies that these tips will wear out, and while I&#39;ve yet to do that, I can see them being damaged in a bag for example. They&#39;re softer than the default Pencil tip, and rubbery to give more friction when touching the glass. It&#39;s not an identical feel, I don&#39;t think, and rather mushy in comparison at first, but you get used to it. Now, picking up a hard Apple Pencil tip feels weird against the glass. I prefer the PenTips to the screen protector variant because it lets me see the screen as it&#39;s meant to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thord’s recommendation, I ordered a box of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pen.tips/collections/pentips/products/pentips_2_plus&quot;&gt;3 – PenTips 2 Plus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PenTips arrived a little over a week ago. Excited I opened the box and immediately put one of the tips on my Apple Pencil and started doodling in GoodNotes. The PenTips added texture, reducing the slipperiness, and provided a more paper-like feel, which improved my precision and control while writing with the Apple Pencil.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Goodlinks send to Drafts Custom Actions</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-send-to-drafts-custom-actions/" />
    <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-send-to-drafts-custom-actions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 20, 2023 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;, I hope you&#39;re taking advantage of Custom Actions. Custom Actions allow you to create your actions to export and share your saved bookmarks. Additionally, you can trigger URL schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ldstephens/how-to-create-custom-actions-in-goodlinks-4dbe4b87c881&quot;&gt;I wrote&lt;/a&gt; the following about Goodlinks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Goodlinks as my read-it-later app. Even though I love it and think that it&#39;s the best reading experience of all read-it-later apps I’ve still been using Instapaper for its Share All Notes feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latest release, version 1.8.5, Goodlinks introduced support for new custom action tags that are going to let me eliminate the need for Instapaper&#39;s Share All Notes: [selection-html], [selection-markdown], and [selection-text] on iOS and iPadOS. These tags will be handy as Goodlinks lacks a built-in highlighting and export highlights feature. Now, I can select text in an article and seamlessly send the selection to Drafts. This is especially handy for creating link posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my five most used Goodlinks send to Drafts actions, which include two new actions specifically for selected text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Title, URL – Drafts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;drafts://create?text={[}[title]{]}{(}[url]{)}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the title and URL of the active article to Drafts as markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Title, URL, Selection – Drafts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;drafts://create?text={[}[title]{]}{(}[url]{)}{ }[selection-text]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the active article&#39;s title, URL, and selected text to Drafts as markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection – Drafts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;drafts://create?text=[selection-text]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the selected text in the active article to Drafts as plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title, Author, URL, Selection – Drafts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;drafts://create?text={# }[title]%0A{*}[author]{*}%0A[url]%0A[selection-text]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the title, author, URL, and selected text in the active article to Drafts as plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Title, URL, Summary – Drafts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;drafts://create?text={[}[title]{]}{(}[url]{)}{ }[summary]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the title, URL, and summary of the active article to Drafts as markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Floppies to iPhones - My 40-Year Love Affair with Technology (and It&#39;s Not Over Yet!)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/from-floppies-to-iphones-my-40-year-love-affair-with-technology-and-its-not-over-yet/" />
    <updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/from-floppies-to-iphones-my-40-year-love-affair-with-technology-and-its-not-over-yet/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 1, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another year wraps up, and the clock is ticking closer to another birthday. I&#39;m turning 79 in a couple of days! Can you believe it? Forty years have whisked by since I first laid eyes on that clunky Compaq Portable at work in 1984. I was instantly hooked, and my fascination with computers, with Apple, with the whole fucking digital revolution has never flickered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey with technology began decades before wrinkles etched themselves onto my face and my knees and hips started protesting when I go for a walk. As I said, it all began in 1984, with a hulking Compaq Portable plopped on my desk at work. With its monochrome screen and dot matrix printer, that beast started a fascination that&#39;s never dimmed in the 40 years since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about that, 40 years! I&#39;ve used a computer almost every single day of my life for four decades. I&#39;ve seen floppy disks morph into flash drives, desktops shrink into MacBooks, iPads, and iPhones, and the internet explodes from a niche curiosity into what it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And speaking of Apple, in 2015, I decided to share my passion with all of you — hence, this blog was born. I’ve loved every minute of it for nine years, over 1,000 posts, and countless cups of coffee later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some might think reaching almost eight decades means slowing down and putting the keyboard aside. But not me! As long as my fingers can type and my mind keeps buzzing with ideas, I&#39;ll be right here, sharing my stories and insights. The tech landscape is ever-shifting, and there&#39;s always something new to explore, a new gadget to try, a new app to try. So, consider this a promise: I&#39;m not disappearing anytime soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Drafts + Day One journaling workflow</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-drafts-day-one-journaling-workflow/" />
    <updated>2024-01-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/my-drafts-day-one-journaling-workflow/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 8, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sparky and Stephen&#39;s deep dive into journaling on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+FrCG3vauU&quot;&gt;Mac Power Users podcast episode 762&lt;/a&gt;: got me thinking about how I approach this practice. So I thought I would chime in with how I journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s my workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick capture with Drafts:&lt;/strong&gt; I use Drafts to write my text entries, it&#39;s perfect for capturing fleeting thoughts or brain dumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly organization:&lt;/strong&gt; My &lt;a href=&quot;https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/1Zk&quot;&gt;Drafts Monthly Journal&lt;/a&gt; keeps everything neatly organized, month by month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-of-month migration:&lt;/strong&gt; At the month&#39;s end, I seamlessly &lt;a href=&quot;https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/2Gs&quot;&gt;share the entire journal with Day One&lt;/a&gt;, preserving my reflections for posterity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day One:&lt;/strong&gt; I use Day One to add images to my journal. I use it on my iPhone to take photos or import them from my camera roll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily dose of nostalgia:&lt;/strong&gt; Day One&#39;s “On This Day” feature is my daily dose of happy memories and self-reflection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple&#39;s Vision Pro - Who actually gives a shit?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-vision-pro-who-actually-gives-a-shit/" />
    <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-vision-pro-who-actually-gives-a-shit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vision Pro? Who gives a shit, right? That&#39;s probably what most folks on the sidewalk would say. And honestly, I get it. Even knowing what this fancy new Apple gizmo is, I can&#39;t muster much excitement either. Maybe I&#39;m just stuck in my old ways, but the idea of strapping a computer to my face just doesn&#39;t do it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s face it, the Vision Pro ain&#39;t exactly chump change. It&#39;s like dropping a house payment on a glorified pair of goggles. For most folks, that&#39;s a tough pill to swallow. Sure, it might be cutting-edge tech and all, but for the average Joe, it&#39;s about as fucking practical as a new Lamborghini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, that&#39;s just me, the grumpy old tech geek. Perhaps there&#39;s a whole world of augmented reality magic waiting to be unlocked, hidden behind those sleek lenses. Maybe I&#39;m missing out on the next big revolution in human-computer interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, for now, I&#39;m content to keep my feet planted firmly in the present, with my trusty old iPhone glued to my hand and my face thankfully unencumbered by high-tech headgear. Maybe someday, the Vision Pro will win me over. But until then, I&#39;ll happily watch from the sidelines, waiting to see if this augmented reality dream turns into reality, or just another expensive fad gathering dust in a corner.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>4 Methods to power-off your iPhone</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/4-methods-to-power-off-your-iphone/" />
    <updated>2024-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/4-methods-to-power-off-your-iphone/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 20, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, knowing how to turn off your iPhone is an important skill. Whether you&#39;re dealing with unresponsiveness or simply want to power down, here are 4 foolproof methods to shut down your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware Button Shutdown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For iPhone X and newer models, press and hold the Side button along with either volume button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide your finger across the on-screen slider to power off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone with a Home button (e.g., iPhone 8 or SE) users can press and hold the Side button to access the shutdown menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Force Shutdown for Unresponsive iPhones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When faced with a frozen iPhone, press volume up, then volume down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press and hold the Side button until the Apple logo appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This method is effective for resolving various iPhone issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settings App Shutdown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to Settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; Shut Down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An alternative for scenarios where hardware buttons are inaccessible or malfunctioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siri-Powered Shutdown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With iOS 15 or higher, instruct Siri to “shut down my iPhone” or “turn off my iPhone.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm the action, either verbally or by tapping the Power Off button in the Siri interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to see the Today View in Apple&#39;s Reminders sorted by Lists</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-see-the-today-view-in-apples-reminders-sorted-by-lists/" />
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-see-the-today-view-in-apples-reminders-sorted-by-lists/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer organizing my day sorted by lists in Apple&#39;s Reminders. While the app provides alternatives like sorting by due date, creation date, priority, and title, the list-based sorting feature is noticeably missing. In this post, I&#39;ll share the workaround I&#39;ve crafted to view my Today tasks sorted by lists until Apple (hopefully) introduces this feature in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Group:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, I create a new Group in Reminders and give it the name “Today&#39;s ToDo List” or any title that suits my preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Lists for Each List:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the “Today&#39;s ToDo List” group, I set up a smart list for each of my existing lists. This involves creating a new smart list and filtering tasks based on the specific list criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/1kkxbzWs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessing Today&#39;s ToDo List:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I want to see my tasks sorted by lists, I simply click or tap on the “Today&#39;s ToDo List” group. This action opens up a comprehensive view of all my tasks for the day, neatly organized by lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/amhFUQc7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, managing my daily tasks is organized in a way that I can quickly identify and prioritize tasks based on their respective lists. Give this method a try to streamline your daily task management in Reminders.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPad Pro rant - the clipboard saga that tests my patience daily</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ipad-pro-rant-the-clipboard-saga-that-tests-my-patience-daily/" />
    <updated>2024-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ipad-pro-rant-the-clipboard-saga-that-tests-my-patience-daily/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 3, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you something: I love my iPad Pro. It&#39;s a fantastic tool for reading, research, and even writing. But here&#39;s the deal: the lack of a decent clipboard manager makes me want to tear my fucking hair out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every. Single. Day. I&#39;m copying and pasting things. Snippets from articles, research notes, half-written sentences. And yet, on the iPad Pro, it&#39;s an exercise in frustration. The measly one-item clipboard is a joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, there are those workaround tactics &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/conquer-the-clipboard-in-ipados-my-system-for-always-on-copying&quot;&gt;that I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; the other day, but let&#39;s call a spade a spade – they&#39;re just that, work-arounds. I get pissed when I start a task that demands copying and pasting; it&#39;s at that moment I reluctantly shift to my Mac. A move that shouldn&#39;t be necessary yet becomes an unavoidable ritual due to the iPad Pro&#39;s clipboard limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should I be compelled to switch devices mid-stream just to manage a fundamental function like copy-pasting? This iPad Pro issue really bothers me, even though I enjoy using it. It deserves better, and it&#39;s high time Apple addressed this glaring shortcoming. Fix it please, Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Can&#39;t quit Alfred? Me neither! But I use these Raycast extensions</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cant-quit-alfred-me-neither-but-i-use-these-raycast-extensions/" />
    <updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cant-quit-alfred-me-neither-but-i-use-these-raycast-extensions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 8, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; since 2016 version 2. My Alfred workflows and muscle memory are so ingrained that moving to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/&quot;&gt;Raycast&lt;/a&gt; just isn’t an option. That said, I&#39;ve got Raycast installed, and I&#39;m currently using the free version, leveraging just two extensions that I find particularly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/extensions/reminders&quot;&gt;Raycast Reminders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; extension. Here&#39;s what it does:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Reminders: You can create new reminders, add notes, set priority, and specify a due date. The due date can be expressed in natural language. For instance, you can say “Remind me tomorrow at 3 PM” to set a reminder for that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Reminders: This command lists all your uncompleted reminders. You can mark them as complete, set their priority, copy details, or open them in Apple&#39;s Reminder app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raycast.com/extensions/calendar&quot;&gt;Calendar My Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; extension. Here&#39;s what it does:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Schedule: View upcoming events for different time frames, from today&#39;s agenda to the weeks ahead. Search for specific events. No more calendar app hopping!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alfred simply has nothing like these two extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When surge pricing hits, your wallet takes a thrashing</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-surge-pricing-hits-your-wallet-takes-a-thrashing/" />
    <updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-surge-pricing-hits-your-wallet-takes-a-thrashing/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 27, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.yahoo.com/lifestyle/wendys-start-testing-uber-style-094524758.html&quot;&gt;hear on the Today show&lt;/a&gt; this morning that Wendy&#39;s is planning to test a dynamic pricing model, also referred to as “surge pricing,” in 2025. This means the prices of menu items will fluctuate based on several factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time of day: Prices might be higher during peak hours like lunch and dinner, and lower during off-peak times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Prices might be adjusted based on the specific location and its customer base or demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall demand: Similar to Uber&#39;s surge pricing, prices could increase if there&#39;s a sudden surge in demand for Wendy&#39;s food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of fast food implementing surge pricing is bullshit. While companies have the right to set their own prices, this approach is nothing more than fucking consumers. It effectively means “we charge extra when you need us most”! Surge pricing at every level is nothing more than ripping off the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A simple trick to snooze emails in Apple Mail</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/a-simple-trick-to-snooze-emails-in-apple-mail/" />
    <updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/a-simple-trick-to-snooze-emails-in-apple-mail/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 1, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever find yourself wanting to snooze emails in Apple Mail? If you primarily use Apple Mail, I have a trick up my sleeve that you might find helpful: &lt;strong&gt;snoozing emails using the Reminders app&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Apple Mail itself doesn&#39;t have a built-in snooze feature, but by leveraging Reminders, you can achieve a similar effect. Here&#39;s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the email you want to snooze.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select some text in the email, like the subject. This helps identify the email later in your Reminders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click the selected text and choose Share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the sharing menu, select Reminders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new reminder is created with the selected text and a link back to the original email in your Mail app. Now, you can set a specific date and time to be reminded about this email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tip: I recommend creating a dedicated Reminders list titled “Snoozed Emails” to keep these reminders organized and easily accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way, you can snooze an email, knowing that the Reminders app will nudge you at the designated date and time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On quality software</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-quality-software/" />
    <updated>2024-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-quality-software/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 9, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thejollyteapot.com/2024/03/9/on-quality-software&quot;&gt;Nicolas Magand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“The other day, I was getting frustrated with the iCloud sync of my RSS feeds in NetNewsWire. It works OK. It syncs between my phone and my computer, what else could I want? Well, it was a bit too slow for my taste, and not 100% reliable, so I subscribed to Feedbin just to make it smoother. It was not about convenience or efficiency, really; it was just about the details.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday I subscribed to Feedbin for the same reason. Besides offering a smoother experience, Feedbin keeps everything in sync across different apps. This means I can use Feedbin with NetNewsWire on my MacBook and Reeder on my iPhone and iPad, and my feed will always be up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The hard lesson that TikTok creators may have to learn</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-hard-lesson-that-tiktok-creators-may-have-to-learn/" />
    <updated>2024-03-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-hard-lesson-that-tiktok-creators-may-have-to-learn/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many creators know, the future of TikTok in the US hangs in the balance. A recent bill passed the House, requiring TikTok to sever ties with its parent company, ByteDance, or face a ban. This situation highlights a crucial lesson for all content creators: &lt;strong&gt;Don’t put your fucking livelihood on a platform you don&#39;t control!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor Lorenz reporting for the The Washington Post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/03/13/tik-tok-ban-react-creators/&quot;&gt;TikTok creators, advocates slam House bill, citing damage to the economy&lt;/a&gt; “If the bill passes the Senate and becomes law, “I will lose my biggest platform as a content creator, stripped from me with no recompense or compensation,” she said.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you build your career on someone else&#39;s platform like TikTok, Facebook, or YouTube, you expose yourself to several risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These platforms hold immense power. They can change algorithms, restrict content, or even shut down entirely, jeopardizing your success and income. You&#39;re essentially building on someone else&#39;s land, and they can change the rules at any time. In this case, the government is in the process of changing the rules for TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/03/13/house-passes-tiktok-ban&quot;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt; “Remember too: China itself bans all foreign social networks. Facebook, Instagram, Threads, Twitter/X, Pinterest — none of them are available in mainland China. It’s bananas that we allow an algorithmically-driven social media app controlled by China here.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Alfred workflow that gets a list of all open Safari tabs</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/alfred-workflow-that-gets-a-list-of-all-open-safari-tabs/" />
    <updated>2024-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/alfred-workflow-that-gets-a-list-of-all-open-safari-tabs/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on March 25, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are times when I&#39;m doing something in Safari, like research, and have a lot of tabs open. Sometimes I would like to have a list of all those open tabs. Well, this is where this workflow comes in. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rknightuk/alfred-workflows/tree/main/workflows/safari-tabs-markdown#what-does-it-do&quot;&gt;Robb Knight has written an Alfred workflow that does exactly that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what it does. It copies open tabs from Safari in various formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy current tab or all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose which of the pages to copy if copying all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy as:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titles only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titles and links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyword trigger is &lt;code&gt;sf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the workflow &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rknightuk/alfred-workflows/tree/main/workflows/safari-tabs-markdown&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robb also has other Alfred workflows that you may be interested in and you can check them out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rknight.me/alfred-workflows/&quot;&gt;Robb Knight – Alfred Workflows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bringing order to my note-taking chaos</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/bringing-order-to-my-note-taking-chaos/" />
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/bringing-order-to-my-note-taking-chaos/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 4, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My note-taking system was a chaotic mess. Determined to get organized, I cleaned it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Up with Apple Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Notes offered initial convenience, but exporting notes was limited to PDFs. I wanted the flexibility of having my notes in accessible files, not a closed-off database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decluttering and Consolidation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step involved a purge of obsolete and unused notes in Apple Notes, slashing the count from a 260 to 69. These remaining notes were then imported into my Obsidian vault, where they were merged with my existing note files. This consolidation means all my notes now reside as individual files within Finder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Streamlined Filing System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For optimal organization, all my files organized in Finder in 3 main folders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My File Cabinet:&lt;/strong&gt; This folder is for all my critical documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Obsidian Vault:&lt;/strong&gt; This folder houses all my notes and highlighted excerpts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing:&lt;/strong&gt; This folder is a central repository for all my writing projects and archived material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effortless File Retrieval with HoudahSpot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By transitioning everything to individual files, I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houdah.com/houdahSpot/&quot;&gt;HoudahSpot&lt;/a&gt; for effortless searching. HoudahSpot for Mac is a powerful and intuitive search tool that revolutionizes how you find files on your computer. No more aimlessly clicking through folders or relying on rudimentary search functions. HoudahSpot empowers you to locate files swiftly using a vast array of criteria, including file names, content, modification dates, and more. Its intuitive interface paired with advanced search capabilities makes it an invaluable tool for anyone seeking to streamline their file management on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drafts send file to iA Writer</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-send-file-to-ia-writer/" />
    <updated>2024-04-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-send-file-to-ia-writer/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 8, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to app for capturing all my text-based ideas. Once I&#39;m ready to turn those ideas into blog posts, I rely on Drafts actions to move them to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ia.net/writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;, my preferred writing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I used a “Save files as” Drafts action, which involved a few cumbersome steps. First, I had to manually change the file extension from .txt to .md (Markdown format for blog posts). Then, I needed to navigate through Finder and select the specific folder (Ideas or Drafts) where I wanted to save the file. This process felt inefficient, and I wanted a more streamlined way to move my content directly to the target folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create an action to do exactly this requires using Drafts &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/settings/bookmarks&quot;&gt;Bookmark&lt;/a&gt;feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bookmark is a reference to a folder in the file system. Bookmarks allow you to grant permissions to work with files in folders that Drafts would not otherwise be able to access due to App Sandboxing security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/actions/steps/services#file&quot;&gt;File action step&lt;/a&gt; can be used to save content from Drafts to files. File action steps can be configured to use a Bookmark by selecting the “Bookmark” destination, and assigning a bookmark name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, I installed the “Save to File in ‘Test’ Bookmark” action, which writes to a file named “Test” in a designated bookmark. I then customized the action for my needs, creating Bookmarks for both my Ideas and Drafts folders in Finder. With these actions in place, I can now save directly from Drafts to the desired folders. Since iA Writer mirrors these folder structures, the files automatically appear in the corresponding locations within iA Writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/S21laMj7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/settings/bookmarks&quot;&gt;Bookmarks | Drafts User Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/1ps&quot;&gt;Save to File in “Test” Bookmark | Drafts Directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Here&#39;s how to summarize YouTube videos using Gemini</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/heres-how-to-summarize-youtube-videos-using-gemini/" />
    <updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/heres-how-to-summarize-youtube-videos-using-gemini/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 9, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I just discovered that Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.google.com/&quot;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; can summarize YouTube videos. This isn&#39;t something that I would do all that often but it could come in handy on occasion so I thought I would share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not familiar with Gemini it&#39;s a large language model Developed by Google AI similar to ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find your target video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the video URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head to &lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.google.com/&quot;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paste the copied YouTube video URL into the prompt field on the Gemini page. Then, type a clear instruction like “Summarize this video” or “What are the key points of this video?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click submit and wait a few seconds. Gemini will analyze the video (using captions) and present you with a summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you find a YouTube video that piques your interest but time is tight, give Gemini a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Can an iPhone be your only computer?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/can-an-iphone-be-your-only-computer/" />
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/can-an-iphone-be-your-only-computer/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 17, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I wondered if an iPhone could be a person&#39;s only computer. After doing a little research I discovered that with iPhone 15 Pro using USB C, it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 15 Pro can handle many tasks with the right setup. Here&#39;s how to turn your iPhone 15 Pro into a more computer-like machine. With its USB-C port, the iPhone 15 Pro can be transformed into a computer by connecting a keyboard, mouse, and external monitor. With a USB-C dongle, you can add additional storage space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this has made you curious I recommend watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3RWQ_pmIRTo&quot;&gt;this video by Stephen Robles&lt;/a&gt;. This is pretty fucking cool but I&#39;ll be sticking with my M1 MacBook Air.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I ditched Apple Podcasts after a week</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-ditched-apple-podcasts-after-a-week/" />
    <updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-ditched-apple-podcasts-after-a-week/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 19, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/&quot;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; on my iPhone to listen to podcasts for almost 10 years. However, recently I&#39;ve been hearing good things about Apple&#39;s Podcast app, so I thought I would give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After using Podcasts for a little over a week, I switched back to Overcast today. I found Podcasts confusing and clunky to use compared to Overcast. While Overcast doesn&#39;t have transcripts of shows, on the rare occasion that I need a transcript for a podcast, I can always go to the Podcasts app to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Roku or Apple TV 4K - Upgrading our streaming device</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/roku-or-apple-tv-4k-upgrading-our-streaming-device/" />
    <updated>2024-04-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/roku-or-apple-tv-4k-upgrading-our-streaming-device/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our trusty old JVC TV, while not a smart one, is and has been a good TV. It was paired with an equally old Roku that had been giving us problems lately. Since the TV itself was still working fine, we decided to upgrade the streaming device. This led us to Roku or Apple TV 4K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One deciding factor was the growing frustration with all the fucking ads on Roku. Then I came across this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2024/04/16/roku-eyes-patent-that-would-inject-ads-into-everything/&quot;&gt;Roku Eyes Patent That Would Inject Ads Into… Everything | Techdirt&lt;/a&gt; and that solidified our decision to move away from Roku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the Apple TV 4K. The speed is fantastic, and the ability to control the TV with my iPhone is a game-changer. No more frantic searching for the remote! We love our new Apple TV 4K!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effortlessly combine Reeder, Instapaper, and Obsidian to enhance your RSS reading experience</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/effortlessly-combine-reeder-instapaper-and-obsidian-to-enhance-your-rss-reading-experience/" />
    <updated>2024-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/effortlessly-combine-reeder-instapaper-and-obsidian-to-enhance-your-rss-reading-experience/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on April 29, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While sitting at my desk the other day, I realized it was time to streamline my RSS reading routine. I was constantly bouncing between apps: Reeder as my RSS client, Goodlinks for saving articles to read later, and Omnivore for highlighting and listening to articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This juggling act felt inefficient. I decided to centralize everything in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reederapp.com/&quot;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt;. With Reeder&#39;s built-in Read Later functionality and its integration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;, I can now manage all my reading needs in one place. I added my Instapaper account to Reeder as a “save to location,” allowing me to also read my saved Instapaper articles directly within Reeder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s not all! By opening an article in Instapaper for highlighting, and thanks to the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.instapaper.com/post/748647273401139200/summaries-custom-article-actions-obsidian&quot;&gt;Obsidian plugin for Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;, my highlights will effortlessly flow into Obsidian. This new approach promises a smoother, more integrated reading experience!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPhone Home Screen - Why one is all I need</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-home-screen-why-one-is-all-i-need/" />
    <updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-home-screen-why-one-is-all-i-need/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on May 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since trading in my two iPads, my iPhone 15 Pro Max has become my daily driver. This shift made me re-evaluate how I use the Home Screen for maximum efficiency. Here&#39;s the thing: I despise cluttered screens with multiple pages, folders, Today View widgets, or widget stacks. So, my challenge was to access everything I needed from a single, Home Screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where the “Choose from Menu” action in Apple Shortcuts comes in. The “Choose from Menu” action in Apple Shortcuts is designed to streamline iOS device automation. It allows you to create customizable menus, presenting options for you to choose from when the shortcut runs. Whether it&#39;s selecting a favorite contact, choosing from a list of apps, or picking a specific destination in a navigation app, the “Choose from Menu” action lets personalize your shortcuts and tailor them to your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use three “Choose from Menu” shortcuts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Apps:&lt;/strong&gt; This shortcut houses apps I don&#39;t use daily but still need occasionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Shortcuts:&lt;/strong&gt; This one groups my most-used shortcuts for quick access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read-Later Apps:&lt;/strong&gt; This shortcut brings up my favorite read-later apps like Omnivore or Instapaper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By placing these shortcut icons on my Home Screen, I have all my essential apps and shortcuts readily available on a single page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned how to create the shortcut from this article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appsntips.com/learn/create-app-launcher-shortcut/&quot;&gt;How to Create an App Launcher Using Shortcuts | appsntips&lt;/a&gt;. It explains how to create it from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach might not be for everyone, but if you want a clutter-free Home Screen, give “Choose from Menu” shortcuts a try!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Change the default app that opens files in iOS and iPadOS</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/change-the-default-app-that-opens-files-in-ios-and-ipados/" />
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/change-the-default-app-that-opens-files-in-ios-and-ipados/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the new iPads were introduced a couple of weeks ago there has been a lot of chatter about what one can and can&#39;t do on an iPad. One of the complaints I encountered was about not being able to set a default app to open certain file types in iPadOS. You know one of those posts about why someone can&#39;t use an iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there is a way sorta. Let&#39;s take a .txt file. The most common files that regular users have are .txt .md or .pdf. The last app to open a file type will be the default until you open it with a different app. Here&#39;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to change the default app that opens a .txt file on your iPad, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Files app and find the .txt file you want to change the default app for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap and hold the .txt file until a menu appears, then select “Share.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the share sheet, you’ll see a list of apps that can open the .txt file. Choose the app you want to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The file will open in the selected app. From now on, whenever you open a .txt file, your iPad will remember this preference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My preference for .txt and .md files is to open in 1Writer and .pdf files to open in the default Preview in iPadOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, iOS doesn’t have a universal way to set a default app for file types, but this method works for accessing files with your preferred app. This works the same way in iOS on iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to scan to “text” on iPhone</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-scan-to-text-on-iphone/" />
    <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-scan-to-text-on-iphone/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, have you ever wanted to scan a document and have it scan to “text” instead of PDF or JPEG? Well, now you can with Simple Scan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://agiletortoise.com/simple-scan/&quot;&gt;Simple Scan&lt;/a&gt; by Greg Pierce of Agile Tortoise is a portable scanner app for iPhones. It allows you to capture high-quality scans of papers, receipts, and photos with just a few taps. You can save your scans as PDF or JPEG files and easily share them via email or cloud services. In addition to PDF or JPEG with &lt;a href=&quot;https://agiletortoise.com/simple-scan/changelog&quot;&gt;version 5&lt;/a&gt; you can now &lt;strong&gt;scan to text&lt;/strong&gt; “&lt;em&gt;“Text” format option shares on the text recognized by optical character recognition as plain text. This can be output to a text file, or shared to other applications as text.&lt;/em&gt;“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a workflow where I can scan a document to “text” and share it directly into &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; Greg&#39;s other great app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>GoodLinks to iA Writer Custom Actions</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-to-ia-writer-custom-actions/" />
    <updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-to-ia-writer-custom-actions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on June 17, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, as I mentioned the other day, I’m switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ia.net/writer&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;for my blogging and writing. This means capturing my ideas directly in iA Writer. Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;GoodLinks&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to read-it-later app, I’ve created some Custom Actions that seamlessly transfer content from GoodLinks to iA Writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/how-to-create-custom-actions-in-goodlinks&quot;&gt;creating Custom Actions&lt;/a&gt; in GoodLinks and it included actions for sending content to Drafts. I’m excited to share three Custom Actions for sending content from GoodLinks to iA Writer with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title, Author, URL, Selection to iA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ia-writer://x-callback-url/new?text=[title]%0A{_}[author]{_}%0A[url]%0A[selection-text]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the title, author, URL, and selected text in the active article to iA Writer as plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selection - iA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ia-writer://x-callback-url/new?text=[selection-text]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the selected text in the active article to iA Writer as plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Title, URL - iA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ia-writer://x-callback-url/new?text={[}[title]{]}{(}[url]{)}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This action sends the title and URL of the active article to iA Writer as markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Easier Blogging Platforms</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/easier-blogging-platforms/" />
    <updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/easier-blogging-platforms/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 12, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I came across David Kennedy’s blog and as I always do when I discover a new indie blog I read his About page and scanned his Archive for articles I might be interested in reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidakennedy.com/blog/easy-websites/&quot;&gt;Easy Websites&lt;/a&gt; post was a response to a post by Giles Turnbull “&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/indie-easy.html&quot;&gt;Make the indie web easier&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need more self-hosted platforms for personal publishing that &lt;em&gt;aren’t Wordpress&lt;/em&gt;. And don’t point me to Hugo or Netlify or Eleventy or all those things - all of them are great, but none of them are simple enough. We need web publishing tools that do not require users to open the Terminal &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;. And we need lots of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like David, I agree with Giles. I’ve been blogging in some form for over 20 years. Most of that time on WordPress.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to love WordPress but in my opinion, it has become way too complicated to use for personal blogs. It’s especially complicated for someone just starting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wanting to get started with a personal blog I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://pika.page/&quot;&gt;Pika&lt;/a&gt;. I also like &lt;a href=&quot;https://bearblog.dev/&quot;&gt;Bear&lt;/a&gt; but it is a little more technical to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So You’re Thinking About Monetizing Your Blog</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/so-youre-thinking-about-monetizing-your-blog/" />
    <updated>2024-07-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/so-youre-thinking-about-monetizing-your-blog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 13, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve at An Almost Anonymous Blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://lwgrs.bearblog.dev/paywalls-pain-and-balance/&quot;&gt;writing about paywalls:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote to myself yesterday saying that I’m resigned to the fact that I’m not going to make “serious” money online. On one hand, it sucks to think that I have all these big plans for myself and realize that no, I’m not going to make a living out of this. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;it’s freeing: I can write anything I want without worrying about the quality, or feel like I need to be a “content creator”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve noticed a growing trend among fellow indie bloggers attempting to monetize their blog. It’s become apparent that something fundamental has changed. The content I once enjoyed reading regularly has changed, and unfortunately, not for the better. These bloggers seem to be adjusting their writing style and content strategy, likely in pursuit of attracting more subscribers. And the frequency of their posts has increased, but the substance has dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question that lingers is whether the income generated from these efforts significantly impacts their lives financially. I bet that in 99.9% of cases it doesn’t. By switching to a monetized model for your blog you will probably piss off a lot of your faithful readers. So why bother?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats to Steve for realizing that he’s not going to make a living from his blog. I’m sure his readers are happy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>10 Years Loving Fastmail</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/10-years-loving-fastmail/" />
    <updated>2024-07-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/10-years-loving-fastmail/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I want to share my experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been using it for a whole decade now, and it’s still fucking fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastmail’s clean and user-friendly interface, with tons of features that let you organize your inbox exactly how you like it. They also prioritize top-notch customer support. Whenever I’ve had a question or issue, like I did today, their team has been quick, friendly, and always resolved it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastmail keeps your emails safe and secure, without any data snooping. Plus, Fastmail integrates contacts and calendars directly into your email. And the best part? You can access your emails, contacts, and calendars from any device, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fastmail offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;free 30-day trial&lt;/a&gt; (no credit card needed!), so give it a try? You might just love it as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remove the Floating Keyboard Bar When Using an External Keyboard on Your iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/remove-the-floating-keyboard-bar-when-using-an-external-keyboard-on-your-ipad/" />
    <updated>2024-07-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/remove-the-floating-keyboard-bar-when-using-an-external-keyboard-on-your-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 17, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, here&#39;s a quick tip for iPad users: If you use an external keyboard, you might find the floating Shortcuts bar obstructing your view. To hide it, tap the keyboard icon on the bar and select &amp;quot;Minimize&amp;quot; or drag the bar to a corner. This keeps it out of your way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The proper order for listing the modifier keys in a keyboard shortcut on Mac</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-proper-order-for-listing-the-modifier-keys-in-a-keyboard-shortcut-on-mac/" />
    <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/the-proper-order-for-listing-the-modifier-keys-in-a-keyboard-shortcut-on-mac/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 24, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you write about Mac keyboard shortcuts, as I do there’s a proper order for listing the modifier keys in a shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leancrew.com/all-this/2017/11/modifier-key-order/&quot;&gt;Dr. Drang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proper order is similar to how you see them down at the bottom left of your keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control (⌃), Option (⌥), and Command (⌘) always go in that order. The oddball is the Shift(⇧) key, which sneaks in just in front of Command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyboard Maestro recognizes this standard order and presents its “hot key” shortcut the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://leancrew.com/all-this/images2017/20171119-Keyboard%20Maestro%20hot%20key%20field.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keyboard Maestro hot key field&quot; title=&quot;Keyboard Maestro hot key field&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Goodlinks - Highlighting is Here!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-highlighting-is-here/" />
    <updated>2024-07-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/goodlinks-highlighting-is-here/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on July 29, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt; is my all-time favorite read-later and bookmarking app. With the release of version 2.0, overnight highlighting is finally here! GoodLinks serves as both a bookmark manager and a read-it-later app. It’s a one-time &#92;$9.99 purchase in the App Store, requiring no account on any web server. Your links and downloaded articles live on your devices, with the option to sync via iCloud. It’s a universal app, available on Mac, iPhone, and iPad. Highlighting is a premium feature for only &#92;$4.99 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a great read-later and bookmarking app at a reasonable price give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.0 Release Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now highlight important information within articles and add notes to them, making it easier for you to remember key passages. Additionally, you can export highlights in Markdown format for seamless integration with other apps. This update also adds support for new Shortcuts actions, allowing you to retrieve, edit, delete, and open highlights. And to further optimize your workflow, the Highlight widget has been introduced, ensuring quick access to your annotated content right from your home screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoodLinks Premium: Highlighting is the first premium feature of GoodLinks Premium, an optional subscription allows you to continue getting access to all new features released one year after your date of purchase. If you purchased the app within the last 12 months, you will get Highlighting for free, with no additional purchase required. For users who purchased the app earlier, it will require you to subscribe to unlock. Once unlocked, these features are yours to keep forever, even if you choose to unsubscribe right after subscribing. GoodLinks Premium brings a more sustainable business model to the app, allowing us to invest in more features and ensuring the app&#39;s long-term development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Paste clipboard content as plain-text on Mac</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/paste-clipboard-content-as-plain-text-on-mac/" />
    <updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/paste-clipboard-content-as-plain-text-on-mac/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 1, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To paste clipboard content as plain text on a Mac, you can use a simple keyboard shortcut. Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy your text as usual (Command + C).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paste as plain text with the following shortcut:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;strong&gt;Command + Option + Shift + V&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will strip any formatting and paste the text as plain text.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When &quot;Check Spelling While Typing&quot; breaks on Mac, do this to fix it</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-check-spelling-while-typing-breaks-on-mac-do-this-to-fix-it/" />
    <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/when-check-spelling-while-typing-breaks-on-mac-do-this-to-fix-it/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 4, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, while doing some writing on my MacBook Air, I realized &amp;quot;Check Spelling While Typing&amp;quot; wasn&#39;t working. I have no idea why it had stopped working. What the fuck? I guess it&#39;s one of the those things that just happen on a Mac occasionally. Anyway if this ever happens to you here&#39;s how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Terminal and copy and paste the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;defaults write -g NSAllowContinuousSpellChecking -bool true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart the affected apps (or your whole computer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac frustrations</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-frustrations/" />
    <updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-frustrations/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 10, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, last Saturday I wrote this in my journal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;04 August 2024 10:56 AM&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday while writing on my MacBook I realized that Check Spelling While Typing was broken. I have no idea how it happened or for how long it had been broken. But it kinda pissed me off. Shit like that doesn&#39;t happen on iPadOS. I love my iPad. In many ways, macOS is fucking frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve committed to using my iPad only for the next week to see if I can get back in the swing of things to make my iPad my main computing device. I know that I can. It&#39;s just different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, after a full week of not touching my M1 MacBook Air, I’ve got some thoughts. The only out-of-the-ordinary thing I did was moving all my tasks from Things to Goodtask, which, honestly, was easier on my iPad than it would’ve been on my MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love my iPad, but it’s not going to replace my Mac. As I’ve realized before, I&#39;ve got too many automations with Alfred, Keyboard Maestro, PopClip, Moom, and Hazel that are deeply ingrained in how I work. I just can’t make the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and by the way, I solved the issues with my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Add words to the Mac dictionary</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/add-words-to-the-mac-dictionary/" />
    <updated>2024-08-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/add-words-to-the-mac-dictionary/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to add words to your Mac&#39;s local dictionary. The most common method is to right-click on a word and select &amp;quot;Ignore Spelling&amp;quot; to remove the red squiggly line. Alternatively, you can use the &amp;quot;Learn Spelling&amp;quot; option to permanently add the word to your Mac&#39;s dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to use Visual Lookup on iOS</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-use-visual-lookup-on-ios/" />
    <updated>2024-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-use-visual-lookup-on-ios/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 13, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Lookup is a handy tool that you can use to identify and learn about plants, trees, insects, wildlife, pets, and more. I knew that there are apps for that but I didn’t know the iOS built-in camera also does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often see a plant, tree, animal, or bug on our property and wonder what it is. Now I know how to identify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a photo of the object that you want to identify.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the Photos app and open the image you want to identify.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for the info button. It looks like a small “i” or a star. It’s typically located at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the info button. This will display details about the photo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap Look Up. This option will appear at the top of the photo information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Lookup will provide information about the identified object, such as its name, species, or relevant details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Freedom to App-Hop</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/freedom-to-app-hop/" />
    <updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/freedom-to-app-hop/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to use whatever apps I feel like using on any given day. That’s just the way I am. The trick is to stop thinking that I need to choose something &lt;em&gt;for good&lt;/em&gt;. I can just pick up whichever tool gives me the best vibes right now and stop worrying about which is “best”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.blog/2024/08/monday-august-12-2024&quot;&gt;Jack Baty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m like this when it comes to writing apps. I feel like I need to pick an app and stick with it. But the truth is, some days I like to write in Drafts other days I like to write in MarkEdit as I’m doing now. And then on another day, I’ll use iA Writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also do this with my RSS aggregator apps. I bounce around between Reeder, NetNewsWire, and Unread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the Mac or iPad conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The trick is to stop thinking that I need to choose something and stick with it forever&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to move a file or folder from one disk to another on a Mac</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-move-a-file-or-folder-from-one-disk-to-another-on-a-mac/" />
    <updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-move-a-file-or-folder-from-one-disk-to-another-on-a-mac/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 17, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To move a file or folder from one disk to another, you must hold down the Command key when dragging its icon from one disk to another. The little Copying Files window even changes to read Moving Files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably already know how to do this but I always forget and have to look it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple tech podcast detox</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-tech-podcast-detox/" />
    <updated>2024-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-tech-podcast-detox/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 18, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I’ve gotten older, I&#39;ve been simplifying my life in various ways. But one area still needs work: my technology addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve built the perfect tech stack apps, devices, and automations all setup just like I want them. I’m no longer interested in tinkering with new apps; it’s a waste of time and money. And I’m definitely not interested in being told I need a Mac to get real work done when my iPad works just fine. Frankly, that’s bullshit! That said I prefer my MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These external pressures come from the Apple tech podcasts I’ve been listening to for years. But I’m done being influenced. So, I’m cutting the influencers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac Power Users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad Pros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Turn Off &quot;iPhone Maybe Too Close&quot; Notification</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-turn-off-iphone-maybe-too-close-notification/" />
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-to-turn-off-iphone-maybe-too-close-notification/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 22, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;iPhone Maybe Too Close&amp;quot; notification is part of the Screen Distance feature introduced in iOS 17. This feature aims to reduce eye strain by reminding users to keep their iPhone at least 12 inches from their eyes. Once disabled, your iPhone will no longer remind you to move it away from your eyes.​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Settings app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Screen Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Screen Distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle off the feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Notes for iOS, iPadOS 18 and macOS Sequoia</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/notes-for-ios-ipados-18-and-macos-sequoia/" />
    <updated>2024-08-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/notes-for-ios-ipados-18-and-macos-sequoia/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 25, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my list of things that I want to look into after the new OS releases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2024/06/10/ios-18-automatic-passkey-update/&quot;&gt;iOS 18 and macOS Sequoia Let Websites and Apps Automatically Update Existing Logins to Passkeys - MacRumors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://macmost.com/whats-coming-in-macos-sequoia.html&quot;&gt;What&#39;s Coming In macOS Sequoia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wL0_ZPnTRuY&quot;&gt;What’s New in Apple Notes in iOS 18?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2024/06/26/icloud-keep-downloaded-option-ios-18-macos-sequoia/&quot;&gt;iCloud &#39;Keep Downloaded&#39; Option Included in iOS 18 and macOS Sequoia - MacRumors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appsntips.com/remove-camera-from-lock-screen-on-iphone/&quot;&gt;How to Remove Camera from Lock Screen on iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/guide/ios-18-notes-app/&quot;&gt;iOS 18 Notes App: All the New Features - MacRumors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2024/07/11/heres-how-apple-intelligence-will-improve-your-writing-in-ios-18yes-even-you/&quot;&gt;Here’s how Apple Intelligence will improve your writing in iOS 18 - 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What’s in My Mac Menubar</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-in-my-mac-menubar/" />
    <updated>2024-08-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-in-my-mac-menubar/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on August 29, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, here are nine Menubar apps that I rely on daily to keep my MacBook workflow smooth, organized, and efficient. Each of these utilities has a special role in making my tasks easier—automating file management, boosting productivity, or keeping my digital life secure. Let me walk you through my go-to apps that make every day more stress-free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hazel&lt;/strong&gt;: Automates file organization with powerful rules, keeping your Mac organized without effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HoudahSpot&lt;/strong&gt;: Supercharges your search with advanced filters, helping you find files faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoink&lt;/strong&gt;: A handy shelf for dragging and dropping files, making file transfers between apps quick and easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DropZone&lt;/strong&gt;: A versatile app streamlining file sharing, moving, and other repetitive tasks with customizable actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/strong&gt;: An AI assistant for quick brainstorming or answering questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PopClip&lt;/strong&gt;: Boosts your productivity by adding a customizable pop-up menu whenever you highlight text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ScreenFloat&lt;/strong&gt;: Captures screenshots that float on top of other windows, letting you reference information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/strong&gt;: A secure and open-source password manager that keeps your credentials safe and accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HiddenBar&lt;/strong&gt;: Helps keep your menubar clutter-free by hiding unnecessary icons, giving you a clean and minimalist look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These apps each add extra efficiency to my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac tip - assign custom keyboard shortcuts for menu items in most Mac apps</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-assign-custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-menu-items-in-most-mac-apps/" />
    <updated>2024-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-assign-custom-keyboard-shortcuts-for-menu-items-in-most-mac-apps/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on September 19, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I want to share a great free app I discovered for Mac:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houdah.com/customShortcuts/&quot;&gt;CustomShortcuts&lt;/a&gt; by Houdah Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CustomShortcuts allows you to create, manage, and customize keyboard shortcuts for menu items in most Mac applications. This is particularly useful for frequently used menu items that don&#39;t have default shortcuts assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Houdah also makes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houdah.com/houdahSpot/&quot;&gt;HoudahSpot&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful alternative to Finder&#39;s search function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give CustomShortcuts a try!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Home Depot and Apple Pay</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/home-depot-and-apple-pay/" />
    <updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/home-depot-and-apple-pay/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 9, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home Depot is gradually rolling out Apple Pay support, according to reports from &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2024/10/08/home-depot-apple-pay-support/&quot;&gt;Chance Miller at 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt; readers and social media. While the company hasn’t officially commented, the rollout started in select stores over the summer and has recently expanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been to Home Depot in a couple of weeks, so I’m not sure if our local store has it yet, but I’ll definitely check. Apple Pay is my go-to, and we buy a ton of shit from Home Depot. It’s always frustrating when I can’t use Apple Pay at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Yoink Bug on macOS Sequoia</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/yoink-bug-on-macos-sequoia/" />
    <updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/yoink-bug-on-macos-sequoia/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 9, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, if you’re using &lt;a href=&quot;https://eternalstorms.at/yoink/mac/&quot;&gt;Yoink&lt;/a&gt; on macOS Sequoia (15.0/15.0.1), you might have noticed an annoying bug where Yoink stops accepting files. I’ve personally run into this issue, and it’s affecting many users of apps that handle file URLs and rely on security-scoped bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root cause? A macOS bug in the “ScopedBookmarkAgent” process, confirmed by a CoreOS engineer on the Apple Developer Forums. Unfortunately, 3rd-party developers can’t fix this—Apple has to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news: macOS 15.1 is expected to fix the issue, and things should return to normal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a temporary workaround, you can:– Quit Yoink (or any other afflicted app)– Using Activity Monitor.app, quit the ScopedBookmarkAgent process– Relaunch Yoink (or any other afflicted app), and it should work again (for a while)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.eternalstorms.at/2024/10/09/psa-a-bug-in-macos-15-sequoia-is-causing-issues-in-yoink-transloader-and-other-devs-apps/&quot;&gt;Matthias&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rant - Internet service provider bullshit</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/rant-internet-service-provider-bullshit/" />
    <updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/rant-internet-service-provider-bullshit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this because I need to get it off my chest. When we moved to New Jersey seven years ago, we got our internet service through Optimum. They had an attractive price for the first year. After that, you go to whatever the current standard price happens to be at the time. Every year since, I’ve had to call and renegotiate a price for the next 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last several years, our price has been $64.99 per month for 1 Gig. Occasionally the negotiations are simple, and they just roll over the previous pricing, but most times, it’s a real pain in the ass. Well, yesterday was one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After haggling with the agent for about 30 minutes, we arrived at a price that was reasonable but not what I wanted but okay. It required replacing the old cable with new fiber optic cable. The agent wanted me to schedule the appointment for the install, but I told him I needed to speak with my wife since she works from home and can’t be disconnected from the internet. I explained that I’d have to call back to schedule an appointment that worked for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things went sideways. The agent said the offer was only valid while we were on the phone and that I needed to agree and schedule the appointment right then. That’s when the shit hit the fan. I told the agent that I didn’t appreciate being put in the position of having to make a decision like that and that I wouldn’t. I told the agent that Optimum could stick their deal where the sun don’t shine. Good bye!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next move was to sign into my Verizon Wireless account on my iPhone and sign up for FIOS. The price was $64.99 per month for 1 Gig with a 4-year price guarantee. I signed up scheduled my install appointment for a time that worked for my wife, and I didn’t have to talk to anyone. Now that’s the way I like it. I should have done this years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I feel better now that I’ve said my piece.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How I manage my clipboard history on iPhone and iPad</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-i-manage-my-clipboard-history-on-iphone-and-ipad/" />
    <updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/how-i-manage-my-clipboard-history-on-iphone-and-ipad/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I was hoping for a clipboard manager in iOS and iPadOS 18. But we didn’t get one. This was no big deal for me because, though. I’ve had a clipboard history manager for iOS since, I think, around 2018 or 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you’re thinking, how is that possible? It’s a little-known clipboard monitoring feature in &lt;a href=&quot;https://eternalstorms.at/yoink/ios/&quot;&gt;Yoink&lt;/a&gt;. I can’t tell you how handy it is to have a clipboard history available, particularly when I’m using my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yoink leverages Picture-in-Picture (PiP) to secretly monitor your clipboard. This lets it stay active even when you close the app. To activate clipboard monitoring, tap the &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; button, then &amp;quot;Monitor Clipboard,&amp;quot; and select a timeout or &amp;quot;No Timeout.&amp;quot; You&#39;ll need to confirm your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this interests you, Federico Viticci has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/ios/yoink-brings-background-clipboard-monitoring-to-ios-and-ipados-15-via-picture-in-picture-workaround/#:~:text=Specifically%2C%20Yoink%20uses%20Apple&#39;s%20Picture,save%20it%20into%20the%20main&quot;&gt;detailed post&lt;/a&gt; explaining how it works and how to set it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - The wonderful rabbit hole of BBEdit</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/" />
    <updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve used the free version of BBEdit starting back when the free version was TextWrangler. The only thing I used it for up to now was for the occasional time that I needed to write something in a plain text editor. When I decided to build a blog using html and css, I decided to pay for the full version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://thejollyteapot.com/&quot;&gt;Nicolas Magand&lt;/a&gt;, now that I own the full version of BBEdit, I figured I should use it for writing markdown blog posts. Most markdown editors have keyboard shortcuts for bold, italic, and links, but not BBEdit. Since Nicolas switched from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thejollyteapot.com/2024/09/27/the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit&quot;&gt;MarkEdit to BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; I figured he must have figured something out for this. And, of course, he had:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can share with you a zip of the some of the script I have added to the Script folder of BBEdit, and now these actions are available in the Script menu, and therefore can be configured with a shortcut in the settings. I’ve recycled a few that I found online (from Dr Drang, Gruber, and more), and they work great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as he said, they work great! Now, in addition to building my blog in BBEdit, I can also write my blog posts. (Shit, I have to figure out how to end a sentence with double space for the period. That is a hard fucking habit to break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the help Nicolas!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If you&#39;re not already using an RSS reader you need to read this</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/if-youre-not-already-using-an-rss-reader-you-need-to-read-this/" />
    <updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/if-youre-not-already-using-an-rss-reader-you-need-to-read-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctorow in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2024/10/16/keep-it-really-simple-stupid/&quot;&gt;latest post&lt;/a&gt; on Pluralistic “You should be using an RSS reader” explains how RSS can help you reclaim your online experience from the enshittification of social media. He goes into detail on how RSS, or Really Simple Syndication, is a simple yet effective way to curate your own, ad-free feed of the web&#39;s best content. With an RSS reader, you can follow your favorite news sources, blogs, and even social media accounts, all in one place. No more endless scrolling through irrelevant content you see what you want, when you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I had a realization: the conduit through which I experience Molly&#39;s excellent work is totally enshittification-proof, and the more I use it, the easier it is for everyone to be less enshittified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conduit is anti-lock-in, it works for nearly the whole internet. It is surveillance-resistant, far more accessible than the web or any mobile app interface. It is my secret super-power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do your self a favor and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2024/10/16/keep-it-really-simple-stupid/&quot;&gt;read the article&lt;/a&gt; from start to finish. You’ll be glad you did.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update - BBEdit rabbit hole</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-bbedit-rabbit-hole/" />
    <updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-bbedit-rabbit-hole/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 24, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about the wonderful rabbit hole of BBEdit and how I now have it set for writing markdown except for one item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Shit, I have to figure out how to end a sentence with double space for the period. That is a hard fucking habit to break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an email from MacOSX Guru suggesting that he does that with a Keyboard Maestro macro. I probably should have asked him for his macro, but instead, I attempted to create my own and was successful. The macro is triggered by double-tapping the spacebar which executes insert text &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; by typing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Canceling Optimum Internet Service? Good Luck!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/canceling-optimum-internet-service-good-luck/" />
    <updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/canceling-optimum-internet-service-good-luck/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 28, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I wrote about my experience with Optimum, our former internet service provider, and how we finally switched to Verizon FIOS. Today, Lisa called Optimum to cancel our old service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a fucking pain in the ass! They eventually processed the cancellation, but the hoops you have to jump through just to cancel should be illegal—and soon will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/10/federal-trade-commission-announces-final-click-cancel-rule-making-it-easier-consumers-end-recurring&quot;&gt;Federal Trade Commission Announces Final “Click-to-Cancel” Rule Making It Easier for Consumers to End Recurring Subscriptions and Memberships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Trade Commission today announced a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library/browse/federal-register-notices/negative-option-rule-final-rule&quot;&gt;final “click-to-cancel” rule&lt;/a&gt; that will require sellers to make it as easy for consumers to cancel their enrollment as it was to sign up. Most of the final rule’s provisions will go into effect 180 days after it is published in the Federal Register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Too often, businesses make people jump through endless hoops just to cancel a subscription,” said Commission Chair Lina M. Khan. “The FTC’s rule will end these tricks and traps, saving Americans time and money. Nobody should be stuck paying for a service they no longer want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commission’s updated rule will apply to almost all negative option programs in any media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Should I Migrate to a Static Site?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/should-i-migrate-to-a-static-site/" />
    <updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/should-i-migrate-to-a-static-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 28, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I&#39;ve become increasingly interested in static sites. This led me to learn some basic HTML and CSS with the goal of recreating my current Bearblog site (ldstephens) as a static site, potentially hosting it on GitHub Pages. I&#39;ve already completed building the new version, so the next step would be migrating all my existing posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major advantage of making this switch would be full ownership of my site, eliminating my dependency on Bearblog and its subscription. This would give me complete control over my content and hosting infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&#39;m facing two main concerns about making this transition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS Feed Impact&lt;/strong&gt;: My primary concern is that changing the RSS feed URL would cause me to lose my current RSS followers, who make up the core of my audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broken Links&lt;/strong&gt;: While all old links would break after the migration, this is less concerning since I no longer receive significant traffic from search results. My readership primarily comes through RSS subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d appreciate hearing from those who have undertaken similar migrations. What was your experience? How did you handle these challenges? Any insights would be valuable in helping me make this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>16GB for everyone - MacBook Air joins the RAM upgrade party</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/16gb-for-everyone-macbook-air-joins-the-ram-upgrade-party/" />
    <updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/16gb-for-everyone-macbook-air-joins-the-ram-upgrade-party/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 30, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time coming—Apple’s new Mac models and the MacBook Air now come with 16GB of RAM as standard, replacing the previous 8GB. I might have to consider upgrading from my M1 Air.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Intelligence first impressions</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-first-impressions/" />
    <updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-first-impressions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 2, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I tried Apple Intelligence on my iPhone, but honestly, I don’t see the point. The way I use my iPhone, it didn’t really add anything useful, and it seemed to drain the battery faster, so I turned it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve kept it turned on on my MacBook for now, but based on my early impressions, it’s still not on par with ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - On Maintaining Streaks</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-on-maintaining-streaks/" />
    <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-on-maintaining-streaks/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 3, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I participated in #100DaystoOffload and the longer it went on, the quality of my posts suffered. I stopped writing because I had something to say, instead, I wrote to keep the streak alive and in doing so I was doing myself and my readers a disservice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now approach things with “dailyish” in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandons-journal.com/re-on-maintaining-streaks/&quot;&gt;Brandon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This supports a point I was making in this opinion post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lstep.xyz/posts/blogging-challenges-are-they-really-worth-it/&quot;&gt;Blogging Challenges: Are They Really Worth It?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update - Static Site</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-static-site/" />
    <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-static-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 5, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a huge thank you to everyone who commented on my original post! After weighing the pros and cons, I&#39;ve decided that BearBlog is where I&#39;ll stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave building my static site a solid shot, creating it in raw HTML and CSS. But upkeep, adding new posts, and updating the feed.xml every time was just too tedious and error-prone. Sure, a static site generator could&#39;ve made things easier, but I found them too complex for me to fully get comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I learned a lot along the way, and it was absolutely worth the effort!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What’s Ahead for America Now?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-ahead-for-america-now/" />
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-ahead-for-america-now/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 6, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to bed at my normal time last night. I didn&#39;t want to stay up and watch the election results come in. I expected a Harris win. I didn&#39;t want to be stressed watching the results come in. I figured I would just get the results when I woke up this morning. Harris didn&#39;t win. Trump won the electoral college and it&#39;s looking like the popular vote as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this election, the United States will become a different kind of country. We have a Republican-controlled Supreme Court, Senate, and perhaps the House as well. With that, the Republicans will be unconstrained with their agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big question is will we be better off or worse off after another four years of Trump?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPhone Notes Missing After Accepting New iCloud Terms? Here’s the Fix!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-notes-missing-after-accepting-new-icloud-terms-heres-the-fix/" />
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-notes-missing-after-accepting-new-icloud-terms-heres-the-fix/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 7, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, Apple recently updated their iCloud terms and conditions, and apparently, after accepting these new terms, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2024/11/07/how-to-fix-iphone-notes-disappearing/&quot;&gt;some iPhone users opened their Notes app to find all their notes gone&lt;/a&gt;! Luckily, I didn’t experience this myself, but some people are having this issue, and I wanted to share a simple fix to help you get those notes back if you’re one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Settings app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap your name at the top (Apple Account settings).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select iCloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap Notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Sync this iPhone is on (toggle it off and back on if it’s already enabled).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Notes app and wait a few minutes for your notes to reappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Your next iPhone could cost $300 more in the Trump administration</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/your-next-iphone-could-cost-300-more-in-the-trump-administration/" />
    <updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/your-next-iphone-could-cost-300-more-in-the-trump-administration/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 8, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If President-elect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/donald-trump/?itid=lk_inline_manual_2&quot;&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; follows through with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/16/trump-tariffs-impact-economy/&quot;&gt;sweeping new tariffs&lt;/a&gt; on anything made in China, your next iPhone could cost roughly $300 more, economists estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/11/08/apple-iphone-trump-tariffs-cost/&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Quietly Introduced iPhone Reboot Code Which is Locking Out Cops</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/" />
    <updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 10, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.404media.co/police-freak-out-at-iphones-mysteriously-rebooting-themselves-locking-cops-out/&quot;&gt;404 Media reported&lt;/a&gt; that law enforcement officials were freaking out that iPhones which had been stored for examination were mysteriously rebooting themselves. At the time the cause was unclear, with the officials only able to speculate why they were being locked out of the devices. Now a day later, the potential reason why is coming into view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Apple indeed added a feature called ‘inactivity reboot’ in iOS 18.1.,” Dr.-Ing. Jiska Classen, a research group leader at the Hasso Plattner Institute, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/naehrdine/status/1854896392797360484?ref=404media.co&quot;&gt;tweeted after 404 Media published&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday along with screenshots that they presented as the relevant pieces of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.404media.co/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/&quot;&gt;Joseph Cox, 404 Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>reality is setting in</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/reality-is-setting-in/" />
    <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/reality-is-setting-in/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through my RSS feed this afternoon, I came across a 9to5 Mac post that said I could get an M3 MacBook Air with 16 GB of RAM and 256 storage for $899 at Amazon or Best Buy. That got my attention, and I thought I should take advantage of that price. It’s $400 off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting here and thinking about it now, reality is setting in. That new M3 Air won’t do anything that my M1 Air isn’t already doing for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Independent blogs lost in search</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/independent-blogs-lost-in-search/" />
    <updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/independent-blogs-lost-in-search/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 12, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been posting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.medium.com/&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; since 2015, and recently, I&#39;ve noticed a significant increase in views. This uptick seems to be related to Google&#39;s shift towards AI-powered search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&#39;s new search algorithm prioritizes content from platforms like Medium, Reddit, Stack Overflow, and Quora over traditional independent blogs. In the end, this trend is pretty fucking disheartening for independent bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like the unique, personal space of an independent blog is getting lost in the noise of the big platforms. For those of us who value independent blogging, it’s a frustrating reminder that the rules of visibility online keep shifting and not in our favor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2024-11-14 Blog update</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-14-blog-update/" />
    <updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-14-blog-update/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, as you know, I’ve been experimenting with a static site. As of today, this site is built entirely with &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmlforpeople.com/&quot;&gt;HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on Netlify. It has no complex server-side processing, databases, tracking scripts, cookies, or analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered using a static site generator but decided it wasn’t necessary for something this simple. Right now, it’s still in a testing phase. I want to make sure everything’s working smoothly, including the RSS feed. If I hit any issues, I might need to move back to Bearblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you spot anything off.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Bluesky? Mastodon? get your own blog instead</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/" />
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this sudden rush to Bluesky and I have started to use it a little more but I keep coming down to the mindset you could just get your own blog instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2024/11/15/bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/&quot;&gt;Lee Peterson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also noticed the rush to Bluesky, so I reactivated my account the other day to see what was happening. Today, I deactivated my account again. I just don’t get the point of social media. To me, it’s nonsensical (my opinion). It’s probably that I’m old school and would rather read your blog in my RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Colophon</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-16-colophon/" />
    <updated>2024-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-16-colophon/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, building this site has been a several-month project. I had a lot of stops and starts, but in the end, I persevered and it’s finally finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is built using static &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmlforpeople.com/&quot;&gt;HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; and is hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;. It automatically deploys when I commit changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ldstep/ldstephens&quot;&gt;public GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding new posts, changing the design, or adding new features, that is done in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New posts are written in Markdown in &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; and copied as HTML to add to a new post in VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using AI to help you build your first static website</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/using-ai-to-help-you-build-your-first-static-website/" />
    <updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/using-ai-to-help-you-build-your-first-static-website/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 18, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newcomer with little or no HTML or CSS experience, you&#39;re going to need guidance building your static site. While YouTube videos and Google searches offer fragmented advice, I found a more comprehensive approach using &lt;a href=&quot;https://claude.ai/new&quot;&gt;Claude AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claude helped me develop HTML and CSS templates. It provided accurate, actionable, and tailored advice that addressed my specific development needs. Claude transformed complex web development concepts into digestible, actionable steps. It also recommended using &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt; for coding and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for hosting and walked me through setting it up via GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do the same thing with ChatGPT but I found Claude to be more precise and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac tip - navigating and selecting text from the keyboard</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-navigating-and-selecting-text-from-the-keyboard/" />
    <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-navigating-and-selecting-text-from-the-keyboard/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 20, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I have Gary’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://macmost.com/&quot;&gt;MacMost Mac Video Tutorials and Tips&lt;/a&gt; in my RSS feed and the other day I saved this video &lt;a href=&quot;https://macmost.com/10-things-you-didnt-know-you-could-do-with-just-the-keyboard.html&quot;&gt;10 Things You Didn’t Know You Could Do With Just the Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; in Goodlinks to watch later. Well, I finally got around to watching it. By the way, if you love the Mac, MacMost is a great resource for tons of tutorials on how to use your Mac better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video highlights hidden macOS tricks for text navigation and selection using the keyboard. Here’s the gist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the arrow keys to move the text cursor back and forth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold the &lt;strong&gt;Shift key&lt;/strong&gt; while using the arrow keys to select text:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Right Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; selects one character at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can type, replace, or paste over the selected text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;strong&gt;Option key&lt;/strong&gt; for word-based movement:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option + Right/Left Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; jumps by word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select one word at a time (&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Option + Right/Left Arrow&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;strong&gt;Up/Down Arrow keys&lt;/strong&gt; to navigate vertically:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select text while moving up or down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option + Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; jumps by paragraph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select paragraphs (&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Option + Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt;), and use &lt;strong&gt;Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; repeatedly to select multiple paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out, you’ll probably pick up a few new tricks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - The App Store era must end, and the Mac is the model</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-app-store-era-must-end-and-the-mac-is-the-model/" />
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-app-store-era-must-end-and-the-mac-is-the-model/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his Macworld article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macworld.com/article/2525708&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; makes a strong argument for why the Mac’s software ecosystem should be the model for iOS and iPadOS. Unlike iOS’s strict, App Store-only model, macOS has a more flexible approach to software distribution that has a balance between security and user freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App Store Apps: These are the most secure and Apple-approved, meeting strict standards. Macs can even be set to run only these apps, but it’s not the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notarized Apps: Developers can distribute apps outside the App Store by submitting them for an automated Apple scan. These apps are safer than fully unverified software, as Apple’s cryptographic signature ensures they’re untampered and from known developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Notarized Apps: These come with no Apple oversight, often from open-source or niche developers. While less secure, they’re still an option for users willing to take the risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system would let iOS and iPadOS users choose what they want without putting their safety at risk, just like Apple does on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cancel a drag and drop on Mac</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cancel-a-drag-and-drop-on-mac/" />
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cancel-a-drag-and-drop-on-mac/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 23, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking this morning and listening to ATP episode 614, the subject of how to cancel a drag and drop came up again. Of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypercritical.co/about/&quot;&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt; knew the answer. I didn’t. I was glad to learn the answer because there have been times that I have started a drag and drop to move files to a different folder, and for some reason, it gets fucked up (user error missing the target folder), and I always panic and want to end the drag and drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to John, all you need to do is &lt;strong&gt;use the escape key&lt;/strong&gt;. I tested it and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, John!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To POSSE or not to POSSE</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/to-posse-or-not-to-posse/" />
    <updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/to-posse-or-not-to-posse/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 25, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt;? It stands for &amp;quot;Publish on your Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere&amp;quot; - basically where you post stuff on your site first, then share it around on social media and whatnot, always linking back to your original post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I&#39;ve been wondering if I should be doing this. And for me, it&#39;s clearly no. Since I don&#39;t use social media, why would I want to put my blog posts there? Sure, maybe I&#39;d pick up a few more RSS subscribers, but that&#39;s not why I&#39;m blogging in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is its own thing. It’s mainly just a place to get my thoughts out there. My RSS followers are my people, and I pick up new ones now and then when other bloggers link to something I wrote. And that’s perfectly fine with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sticking My Head in the Sand (But Not Really)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/sticking-my-head-in-the-sand-but-not-really/" />
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/sticking-my-head-in-the-sand-but-not-really/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 26, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent way too much time over the last 12 months paying way too much &lt;em&gt;fucking&lt;/em&gt; attention to political news. The US election is over. I’m over it. I’ve purged all news from my RSS feed, including any blogs that can’t resist regularly interjecting politics into their content. Gone. Done. Also? No more 24-hour news channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m old. I want to enjoy what’s left of this ride. I don’t want to spend my final years fretting about everything that’s coming down the pike that I don’t agree with. Do I care? Hell yes, I care. But let’s be real, there’s nothing I can do to change it. And let’s face it, nobody’s going to be thrilled with everything that’s coming anyway, no matter who you voted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, am I sticking my head in the sand? Nope. I’m still watching the national news on broadcast TV, you know, the regular stuff that gives me what I need to know without dragging me into the political abyss. I’ll stay informed, but the days of letting politics hijack my fucking sanity are over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - My advice to iPhone users considering a move to Android</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/" />
    <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 1, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed that some bloggers I follow are switching from iOS to Android. I’m sure each of them has their reasons for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved from Android to iOS 10 years ago. Android has probably changed a lot since then, but I don’t see myself ever returning. I left Android because I wanted to stop using Google services. In addition, iOS offered better security and privacy, and consistent OS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://merecivilian.com/my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/&quot;&gt;MereCivilian&lt;/a&gt; recently switched to Android and offers some good advice for those who may be considering the switch. As I mentioned above, I stopped using Google services long ago and wouldn’t want to start again, which would be necessary with an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Switching blogging engines</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/switching-blogging-engines/" />
    <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/switching-blogging-engines/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 3, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just read Jack Bay’s post &lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.net/2024/12/from-hugo-to-ghost-and-back-again/&quot;&gt;From Hugo to Ghost and back again&lt;/a&gt; about how often he switches up his blogging engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hear you all giggling. Ha ha very funny, Jack changed his blog again. I get it. Most normal people don’t change blogging engines every month or two.[…] Also, and maybe most importantly, I prefer static websites. The arguments in favor of static websites are enough, but they aren’t why I want a static site. It &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; better having a static website. The actual publishing part can be a pain in the ass (:::cough::, Hugo) but the results are worth it. A folder full of HTML files and some images, starting on my local drive and synced to a simple web server…mmmmm, yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me a bit of myself. You may have noticed that after switching this blog to a static site, I’ve moved it back to Bearblog and then back to static a couple of times over the last few weeks. Much like Jack, it just feels better to have a static website. I take pride in something I’ve built, and my content isn’t locked inside Bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I agree – publishing with a static site is a pain in the ass, but it’s worth the extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stop the constant switching, I decided to close my Bear account. In the end, this entire site is just a folder full of HTML files on my SSD, synced to GitHub and hosted on Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drafts - the best $20 bucks I spend every year</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-the-best-20-bucks-i-spend-every-year/" />
    <updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-the-best-20-bucks-i-spend-every-year/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 7, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I want to give a shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;! It’s the best $20 bucks I spend every year. I first installed Drafts in 2014, when it was only available on iOS. Then, in 2019, Drafts came to the Mac. Drafts is my all-time favorite app and is where every bit of text starts: blog ideas, random thoughts, notes, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have an idea or a thought, I immediately open Drafts and save it. It’s my go-to for quick note-taking. I use it to outline, draft, and format all my blog posts in Markdown. I keep everything organized with tags and workspaces. It’s also my personal information dump; with its amazing search, Drafts serves as my central repository for all the random bits of info I collect. On top of that, I’ve set up custom actions that let me do just about anything with my text: sending it to other apps, emailing it, saving it as a file, formatting it, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never tried Drafts, you gotta give it a try. There’s a free version to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Thoughts On Mangione</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-thoughts-on-mangione/" />
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-thoughts-on-mangione/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post December 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about the state of healthcare in America in light of the murder of the United Healthcare CEO. I have hesitated writing about how I feel about this situation, but this morning, I read Dave Rogers, Nice Marmot &lt;a href=&quot;https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2024/December_2024.html#note_2570&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about this very subject, so I thought I would say what I’m thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t given a great deal of thought to how I feel about the murder of that CEO. (I’m not mentioning his name mostly because I can’t recall it at the moment; but also because I don’t think he’s worthy of _“Say his name!”_respect.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trae Crowder is a stand-up comedian who has a YouTube channel called Liberal Redneck. I watch his videos because I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a laugh, and his are funny but also intelligent. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/aUcwZTWv2PY?si=ko0YNmGuWEo1KQfm&quot;&gt;I found this one particularly thought provoking&lt;/a&gt;, which is significant because I’d been kind of going out of my way &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to think about it. My reaction is that I don’t find much to disagree with in his comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before reading Dave’s post, I read a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-lede/what-the-murder-of-the-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-means-to-america&quot;&gt;New Yorker article&lt;/a&gt; by Jia Tolentino, “What the Murder of the United Healthcare C.E.O. Means to America&amp;quot; and I wanted to point out that United Healthcare denies 32% of insurance claims. Yep, nearly a third of claims submitted to this company are denied. That’s double the industry average, according to The New Yorker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Yorker quoted a person who posted on Reddit’s r/nurses forum, whose profile describes her as an I.C.U. nurse, wrote, &amp;quot;Honestly, I’m not wishing anyone harm, but when you’ve spent so much time and made so much money by increasing the suffering of the humanity around you, it’s hard for me to summon empathy that you died”. Thompson, who became C.E.O. in 2021, had raised annual profits from twelve billion dollars to sixteen billion dollars during his tenure. He received more than ten million dollars in compensation last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denying people the care they desperately need is fucking wrong and cruel. Yet, this level of corporate-driven harm has become so normalized in America that we barely blink at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m conflicted about the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Digital responsibilities</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-digital-responsibilities/" />
    <updated>2024-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-digital-responsibilities/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/digital-responsibilities&quot;&gt;Manu&#39;s blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a post going viral on Hacker News. After being shared on Hacker News by someone, his website experienced a massive traffic spike that would make most website owners nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What caught my attention wasn&#39;t just the traffic surge but Manu&#39;s reflections on the broader question of online content sharing and the potential impact of sending unexpected waves of internet traffic to someone&#39;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I’m wondering, if my site was big enough to cause problems, would then be my responsibility to be careful what I link to? Or should I just assume that other people out there know what they’re doing and I can keep linking without a second thought? My gut reaction tells me that it’s not really my responsibility to worry about the way other people run their sites but maybe I’m wrong and I should worry about that. &lt;strong&gt;I’d love to know what you think because this is one of those situations where I can see good arguments on both sides.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ldstephens is a static site that runs on Netlify’s Free Plan. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 GB monthly bandwidth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 GB storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progressive usage notifications at 50%, 75%, 90%, and 100% of monthly limits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic site suspension if monthly limits are exceeded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick upgrade option to continue site availability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see a Hacker News viral moment could use up 100 GB of bandwidth fairly easily and could potentially suspend my site until the next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what Manu is asking is how I would feel if he shared one of my posts and it, for some reason, went viral and, exceeded my bandwidth limit and knocked my site offline. Would I feel that he had any responsibility? My answer is no. It’s my responsibility to manage my site, and he is welcome to share anything that I write, just as I’m sharing what he wrote in this post and responding to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>App Defaults</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-12-24-app-defaults/" />
    <updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-12-24-app-defaults/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated December 15, 2024: Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaults.rknight.me/&quot;&gt;Hemispheric Views 097 - Duel of the Defaults&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Client: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Drafts, Apple Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: GoodTask/Reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone Photo Shooting: iOS Camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo Management: Photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud File Storage: iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS: Reeder Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacts: Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari, Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat: Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading: Kindle Paperwhite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcast: Overcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts, iA Writer, VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launcher: Alfred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spreadsheets: Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shopping Lists: Reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts: Overcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Management: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather: Carrot Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple&#39;s unwanted 18.2 Mail makeover</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover/" />
    <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated my iPhone to iOS 18.2 the other day and was pissed to find my Mail app hijacked by the categories and giant sender icons. I was more pissed that the update just forced these changes on me without even asking if I wanted these shitty&lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover#fn:1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After fucking around for a while, I figured out how to turn these annoying new features off and return to the Mail interface that’s worked perfectly fine forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable sender icons, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Settings app on your iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down and tap “Apps”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and tap “Mail”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locate the “Message List” section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle off the switch next to “Show Contact Photos”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable categories, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Mail app on your iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the “More” button (three dots) in the upper right corner of your inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “List View” from the pop-up menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>People don’t give a shit about Vision Pro</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/people-dont-give-a-shit-about-vision-pro/" />
    <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/people-dont-give-a-shit-about-vision-pro/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 27, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in January, I wrote a post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-vision-pro-who-actually-gives-a-shit&quot;&gt;Apple’s Vision Pro: Who actually gives a shit?&lt;/a&gt;. “Vision Pro? Who gives a shit, right? That’s probably what most folks on the sidewalk would say. And honestly, I get it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Lisa and I we went to the Apple store to buy her a new iPhone. It was my Christmas present to her. We traded in an iPhone 11 and purchased an iPhone 16 Pro. Considering the size of the crowd in the store, we were there for a little over two hours. That included purchasing the new phone, processing the trade-in, and the setting up of the new phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vision Pro had its own table in the back corner of the store. I was keeping my eye on it because I was curious if anyone would go over and check it out. In the two-plus hours that we were in the store, not one person went to the table to check out the Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was right. People just don’t give a shit about the Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Year 2025</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/new-year-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/new-year-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 1, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are again - another year has flown by! They seem to go by faster and faster, and 2024 was no exception. It’s hard to believe we’re already in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m not one to dwell too much on the past, I will say that 2024 was a good year for Lisa and me. Looking ahead, my hope for 2025 is to continue living a healthy lifestyle and making the most of each day. I’ve got a couple of significant milestones coming up this year, which I’ll likely share more about when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year, and thank you for being a reader!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I don’t care about your politics</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/" />
    <updated>2025-01-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samhawken.com/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/&quot;&gt;Sam Hawken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a long-standing position on politics: don’t make your politics my problem, and I won’t let mine become yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that I don’t have strong political feelings because I do, but I am saying that I’m not interested in discussing that topic with anyone I wouldn’t hug. This seems to be the healthiest approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether I agree with or disagree with your politics, I don’t want to read about them. If you must write about them, I’ll remove you from my RSS feed. I agree with Sam. We all have political views, and as divided as we are over those views, the healthiest approach is to not fucking discuss them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I’ve been doing it wrong</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/" />
    <updated>2025-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 6, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using GitHub all wrong for this site. Instead of working from a cloned repository, I was just using a regular folder of files on my computer. Whenever I wanted to add a new post or make changes, I’d edit them in VS Code, then drag and drop the updated files directly into GitHub’s web interface. I knew this wasn’t the right way to do it, but I didn’t know any better. So, I started searching YouTube for a better way to handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iv8rSLsi1xo&quot;&gt;GitHub Tutorial - Beginner’s Training Guide - YouTube&lt;/a&gt; that helped immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I needed to do was install GitHub Desktop and I needed to clone the repository locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now GitHub Desktop connects GitHub, my local repository, and VS Code together. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting to GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub Desktop links directly to my GitHub account, so I can easily clone repositories and sync my changes with the remote repositories on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing My Local Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: When I clone a repository using GitHub Desktop, it creates a local copy on my computer. This is where I make changes and commit updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Visual Studio Code (VS Code)&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve set VS Code as my default editor in GitHub Desktop. When I click “Open in Visual Studio Code,” it opens my local repository in VS Code, ready for me to start coding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping Everything in Sync&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write and edit my code in &lt;strong&gt;VS Code&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Desktop tracks the changes I make and lets me commit them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I’ve committed, I can push my changes to GitHub or pull updates from the remote repository when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, taking the time to learn GitHub Desktop has made managing my static site so much easier. I can jump into VS Code to edit, track changes locally, and sync it all with GitHub in just a couple of clicks. It’s been a fucking game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ldstephens - notes</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-notes/" />
    <updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-notes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 7, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I have now added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/notes&quot;&gt;notes page&lt;/a&gt; to the blog. Notes are shorter random posts, kinda like a microblog or what I would post on social media if I used social media, which I don’t. Notes include link posts as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Send articles from iPhone to Kindle for reading later</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later/" />
    <updated>2025-01-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 9, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I saved an article to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt; to read later. Today I decided to read it and discovered that the article is a 33 minute read. I didn’t want to take the time to read it right then, I thought that’s something that I would like to read on my Kindle Paperwhite while I’m in bed this evening&lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later#fn1-27410&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. The next question is how the hell do I get this article on my Kindle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was easy. I opened the article on my iPhone and saved it to my Kindle via the share sheet save to Kindle. I wrote this to share a helpful tip I didn’t know about myself. If you’re interested in doing the same thing, I hope you find it useful!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Social networking alternatives for the Meta- and Musk-averse</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-social-networking-alternatives-for-the-/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-social-networking-alternatives-for-the-/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 10, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/23429095/twitter-social-network-alternatives-mastodon-reddit-tumblr-cohost&quot;&gt;Verge article&lt;/a&gt; in my RSS feed about alternatives for the Meta- and Musk-averse and wondered if blogging was provided as an alternative. Well, you probably guessed blogging was not provided as an alternative—just more social media platforms. Look folks maybe it’s time to quit social media and start a blog. If what you’re using isn’t already enshittified it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPhone one screen setup</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-one-screen-setup/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-one-screen-setup/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 13, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, For the new year, I decided to clean up my iPhone&#39;s Home screen. While I&#39;ve been using just one screen for a while now, I wanted to give it a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I removed all apps from my Home screen except for those in the Dock. My plan was to only add back the apps I use most often. For everything else, I can just use Spotlight search or App Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my Home Screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tmjrAb7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What happens on your device, stays on your device – until it doesn’t</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 15, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://decoding.io/2025/01/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/&quot;&gt;Zsolt Benke&lt;/a&gt; for sharing this post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.obdev.at/blog/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/&quot;&gt;Objective Development Blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS Sequoia introduces another new feature labelled Help Apple Improve Search, which sends and stores various search queries from Safari, Spotlight, and other sources to improve search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature, too, is enabled by default and is well hidden at the very bottom of System Settings &amp;gt; Spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that I had disabled this setting on my iPhone, and iPad but not on my Mac so I disabled it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Celebrated Lawyer ‘Fires’ Meta As A Client Over Zuck’s ‘Neo-Nazi Madness’</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 16, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2025/01/15/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/&quot;&gt;Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And earlier this week, he announced that he has “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/marklemley.bsky.social/post/3lfnpmxtam22r&quot;&gt;fired Meta as a client&lt;/a&gt;.” Lemley was representing Meta in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2023/07/11/a-bunch-of-authors-sue-openai-claiming-copyright-infringement-because-they-dont-understand-copyright/&quot;&gt;Kadrey v. Meta lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; regarding Meta’s use of books in training its AI. And, as the docket shows, on Monday, he withdrew as an attorney for Meta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Lemley noted on various social media profiles, he cannot stomach what he sees as Zuckerberg’s embrace of nonsense and this is how he is responding to “Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook’s descent into toxic masculinity and Neo-Nazi madness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👏👏👏&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>James’ Coffee Blog</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/james-coffee-blog/" />
    <updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/james-coffee-blog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 17, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, the other day, I was reading a blog post (wish I could remember whose!) about the indie web. It had several links, and I clicked one that took me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;indieweb.org&lt;/a&gt;. While browsing there, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/&quot;&gt;James’ Coffee Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really hooked me was James’ content. It’s a mix of tech and personal topics. I spent some time exploring his site and found tons of interesting articles to dive into. Needless to say, James’ Coffee Blog is now part of my RSS feed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not already following James, check out his site. I think you’ll find it worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that I highlighted while reading one of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/01/15/static-dynamic/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a static site is significant to me because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static sites are fast (when engineered with performance in mind, of course!0. There is a significantly reduced admin tax. If my publishing tool goes down for any reason, my static site can still be available. I enjoy having folders of text files to edit: both markdown for posts and HTML for templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t agree more, static sites offer speed, simplicity, and the satisfaction of working directly with text files!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Don’t forget your RSS readers</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/dont-forget-your-rss-readers/" />
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/dont-forget-your-rss-readers/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 18, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking analytics for ldstephens, it appears to receive relatively few direct page views. This can sometimes be discouraging. However, I must keep in mind that my target audience isn’t solely comprised of direct visitors but rather the 360+ RSS followers who are most likely to read my posts through their RSS reader app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Zed fonts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/" />
    <updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 21, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you prefer mono fonts for writing and coding. I recently discovered a new mono-spaced font that you might be interested in. Macosguru &lt;a href=&quot;https://bicycleforyourmind.com/links%20of%20note%202025-01-21&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about a new text editor he found and also mentioned that the app’s default font, Zed mono, was clean and well-designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zed.dev/&quot;&gt;Zed&lt;/a&gt; is a new text editor which is built around the collaboration between humans and AI. I am not interested in that particular activity but it is an interesting addition to the world of text editors. It is snappy, clean, and modern. I don’t have a need for it, having immersed myself in Emacs. But if you are looking for an editor, I would give this a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about Zed. I loved the fonts that the editor uses as default. They have made them available.&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zed-industries/zed-fonts&quot;&gt;The Zed Mono and Sans typefaces, custom built from Iosevka&lt;/a&gt;. I can’t resist a free font, specially a well-designed, clean one. Get them to use in your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Macosguru, I’m not interested in Zed’s text editor, but I did download the mono fonts. I’m currently typing this in MarkEdit using the Zed mono-spaced font, and I like it. I’m going to use it for a while and see if it sticks for me. Check out the Zed editor and Zed fonts for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Intelligence and iPhone battery drain</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’ve recently noticed that my iPhone 15 Pro Max battery is draining faster than usual. I thought. Is this just me? Definitely not. &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.macrumors.com/threads/apple-intelligence-battery-drain.2442119/&quot;&gt;A lot of people&lt;/a&gt; are discussing this issue after enabling Apple Intelligence. For now, I’ve disabled it because I don’t find it particularly useful on my iPhone. After disabling Apple Intelligence my battery life is back to what it was before enabling it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You Can Build Your Own Static Blog - Here&#39;s How!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I bet a lot of you with a personal blog on platforms like Bear Blog, Pika, Write.as, have thought about building your own blog at some point. I know I was curious—until I finally decided to do for it! I didn’t have much knowledge of HTML or CSS, but I knew just enough to want to give it a shot. Plus, I figured I could use AI tools like ChatGPT or Claude to help me get started and tackle the stuff I didn’t know how to do. And the result? This blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve thought about creating your own blog too but felt overwhelmed by HTML, CSS, or all the technical details. Don’t worry, you’re not alone! The great news is that you can build a basic static blog site without needing a static site generator, the terminal, or advanced coding skills. With a little help from AI tools, it’s totally doable to create a site with an Atom feed for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down step by step. I’ve asked ChatGPT for assistance with this task. The final outcome is a very basic, static blog that serves as a step-by-step guide to help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Understand the Basics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving in, let’s get some quick definitions out of the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static site&lt;/strong&gt;: A website that doesn’t require a database or fancy backend. Think of it as a collection of simple HTML files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atom feed&lt;/strong&gt;: A type of RSS feed that allows people to subscribe to your blog and get updates when you post new content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be an expert at these. Just know that they’re essential to making a functional blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Pick the Right Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can do a lot of the heavy lifting for you. Here are some tools you’ll use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Code Generators&lt;/strong&gt;: Platforms like ChatGPT can generate the HTML, CSS, and Atom feed for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text Editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a simple editor like Visual Studio Code (free) to tweak the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting Service&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub Pages or Netlify are great free options for hosting your static blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Create the CSS File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by asking the AI to create a CSS file for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create a CSS stylesheet for a blog with a header, main content area, and a footer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what the AI might generate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;/* styles.css */
body {
   font-family: Arial, sans-serif;
   line-height: 1.6;
   margin: 0;
   padding: 0;
}

header {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   padding: 1rem 0;
   text-align: center;
}

main {
   padding: 2rem;
   max-width: 800px;
   margin: 0 auto;
}

footer {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   text-align: center;
   padding: 1rem 0;
}

nav a {
   margin: 0 1rem;
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

nav a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}

.blog-list {
   margin-top: 2rem;
}

.blog-list a {
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

.blog-list a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;styles.css&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Link the CSS File in Your HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, update your HTML files to reference the CSS file. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;My Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Welcome to My Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            This is the home page of my blog. Use the navigation to explore
            posts!
         &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the homepage for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Create the Blog Page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, ask the AI to generate a separate page for listing blog posts. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an HTML file for a blog page listing multiple posts with links to individual post pages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;section class=&amp;quot;blog-list&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Recent Posts&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post2.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 2&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post3.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 3&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the blog page for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6: Create Individual Blog Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each blog post, create a separate HTML file. Here’s an example for &lt;code&gt;post1.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;../styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;article&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the content of Post 1. Welcome to my first blog post!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/article&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place this file in a &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder (e.g., &lt;code&gt;blog/post1.html&lt;/code&gt;). Repeat for each new post, updating the links in &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 7: Create an Atom Feed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the AI to generate an Atom feed for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an Atom feed for a blog with multiple posts, each with its own link and publication date.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update the feed as needed when you add new posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 8: Host Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your files, it’s time to put them online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re using GitHub, create a new repository and upload your files. Go to the repository settings and enable GitHub Pages. Your blog will be live at &lt;code&gt;https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo-name/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netlify&lt;/strong&gt;: Drag and drop your files into Netlify, and it will instantly publish your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 9: Update Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you write a new post, you’ll need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new HTML file for the post in the &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link it to the &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt; page under the &amp;quot;Recent Posts&amp;quot; section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;code&gt;atom.xml&lt;/code&gt; feed with the new post details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the updated files to your hosting service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a static blog doesn’t have to be complicated. With AI tools to generate code and free hosting platforms to get your site online, you can create a functional blog. Once it’s live, you’ll have your space to share your thoughts with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Now I’m doing Yoga</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/" />
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 25, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, at 80, I like to think I’m pretty fit for my age. I’m 6 feet tall and weigh 165 pounds. Trix, our dog, and I walk 2 miles every single day, no exceptions. We’ve got a 10-acre property that keeps me plenty busy. In the winter, we heat the house with firewood I cut and split myself. I have a 35-ton log splitter that makes the job easier. Staying active is just who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I took a tumble down the basement stairs. Luckily I didn’t get hurt badly. A sore hip, sore back, and a gash on the palm of my left hand from attempting to catch myself. Oh yeah, my Apple Watch didn’t detect my fall. What the fuck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t my only fall over the last few years. As you age, poor balance becomes a concern, as the risk of falls increases. So with this last fall, Lisa insisted that I start doing Yoga that focuses on improving balance and core strength. So to get her off my back I agreed to start doing Yoga three times a week. Week one I realized how shitty my balance is. Week two I’m starting to see some slight improvement. Now on top of everything else that I do, I’m doing yoga three times a week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 29, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a bit of a rollercoaster when it came to my blog setup. I started the day with a plan after reading Herman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://herman.bearblog.dev/manifesto/&quot;&gt;Bear Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; post: move ldstephens back to Bearblog. This change would reduce the friction associated with posting to a static site, and Bearblog would provide me with built-in analytics. Seemed like a win-win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the afternoon, I tackled a necessary but tedious task in Bearblog—changing all the canonical links to alias and moved the DNS server setting to Bearblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, plot twist! By the evening, I decided to move ldstephens back to Netlify. At the end of the day, I just love that I built this site myself. There’s something satisfying about knowing it&#39;s mine, running on my own setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all that back and forth, I&#39;m right back where I started. But hey, sometimes you have to try something just to confirm that what you had was already the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>11ty project</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/" />
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 3, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to replicate this site in 11ty as a learning project. The first thing I did was install Node.js. When I came to the 11ty install step, the install failed. After some additional attempts, I determined the problem might be the version of Node.js that I installed. So I uninstalled Node.js. Today, I’ll install a different version and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop again</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 4, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to change the layout and design of this blog. Since it&#39;s a static site running on Netlify, making changes isn&#39;t always smooth. And, of course, I ended up breaking the fucking site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I had to point the DNS back to Bearblog, where I keep a duplicate version for moments like this when I inevitably mess up the static site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now (and maybe longer, depending on how things go), the blog is running on Bearblog until I get the new layout and design sorted.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop… again (but fixed now)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was fun. The new layout and design are finally done, and everything is back up and running on Netlify where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breaking the site (because, of course, I did), we’re back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Instapaper</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; was my go-to read-it-later app. Over the years it’s had a long and convoluted life some good and some not so good. During one of those not-so-good times, I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, Instapaper has been getting a lot of attention so every time the app gets updated I install it to test it out. Today I got an email from the developer announcing version 9.1 so I installed it and I’m using it in place for Goodlinks for the time being. One of the things that I like about Instapaper is the way it integrates with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reederapp.com/classic/&quot;&gt;Reeder Classic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll continue using Instapaper, but if I do, the free version is sufficient for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sleep Number vs. my snoring</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/" />
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 6, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently got a Sleep Number bed. I snore, which makes it difficult for Lisa to sleep. The bed has a snore setting that automatically adjusts its position to help reduce snoring. When activated, it gently raises the head of the bed by a few degrees to open airways and improve breathing. So when I snore, Lisa can adjust my side of the bed until I stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, when I woke up, I was surprised to find myself almost upright. Lisa said she kept adjusting the bed until I quit snoring–and that was the position when I finally stopped. At this rate, I might as well start sleeping in a recliner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the Sleep Number bed has been wonderful for my lower back.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>U.K. orders Apple to let it spy on users’ encrypted accounts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/" />
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 7, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/02/07/apple-encryption-backdoor-uk/&quot;&gt;Joseph Menn, The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security officials in the United Kingdom have demanded that Apple create a back door allowing them to retrieve all the content any Apple user worldwide has uploaded to the cloud.[…] The British government’s undisclosed order, issued last month, requires blanket capability to view fully encrypted material, not merely assistance in cracking a specific account, and has no known precedent in major democracies.[…] Rather than break the security promises it made to its users everywhere, Apple is likely to stop offering encrypted storage in the U.K., the people said. Yet that concession would not fulfill the U.K. demand for backdoor access to the service in other countries, including the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is fucking crazy shit! If there’s a backdoor, hackers and cybercriminals will eventually find a way in, putting our security and privacy at serious risk. Our personal data could be stolen, leading to identity theft, financial fraud, and other attacks. It wouldn’t just be law enforcement using it—bad actors, including hackers and even foreign governments, could exploit the same weakness, violating users’ right to privacy and secure communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple could pull iCloud from the UK</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/" />
    <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 9, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you who read my posts are in the U.K. You may have already read this. Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2025/02/07/could-apple-pull-icloud-services-from-uk/&quot;&gt;Tim Hardwick, MacRumors&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“A more dramatic response from Apple would involve completely removing iCloud services from the UK. While this would protect Apple&#39;s encryption standards, it would severely disrupt millions of UK users who rely on iCloud for photo storage, device backups, and document syncing. Users would need to find alternative cloud storage solutions and potentially lose access to years of accumulated data.”&lt;/em&gt; Are you concerned about this possibility?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cracked Corn 🌽</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/" />
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 10, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/QVy072ds.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeding time around here is no joke! We go through 100 pounds of cracked corn every week to keep the deer and wild turkeys happy as they wander our 10-acre property. Our place is actually a Certified Wildlife Habitat with the state of New Jersey, and we love all the creatures that call it home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we go through 40 pounds of birdseed for all the birds. Of course, the raccoon has figured out a little trick—every night, it climbs the tree, hangs off the bird feeder, and dumps the seed just so it can feast. Smart little guy! I haven’t spotted the groundhog yet this year, but I’m sure it’ll make an appearance soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On - Which HTML element are you [Quiz]?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 13, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James at James’ Coffee Blog created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/02/13/html-quiz&quot;&gt;fun quiz&lt;/a&gt; called “Which HTML element are you?” It has ten questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the quiz and “I’m the &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; element! You’re great at gathering ideas from different sources and putting them together”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This post was generated using Eleventy</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/this-post-was-generated-using-eleventy/" />
    <updated>2025-02-19T19:39:26Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/this-post-was-generated-using-eleventy/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 19, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the title suggests, this blog is now generated using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/&quot;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt; also known as 11ty. You might remember that I had planned to rebuild the blog using 11ty, and after a lot of trial and error, I finally made it happen. The process wasn&#39;t easy, but I&#39;ve learned a ton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between a plain static site and one generated with Eleventy is huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When managing a static site manually, everything had to be created and organized by hand HTML, CSS, and all the files. Each page was its own separate HTML file, so if something like the navigation needed updating, every page had to be changed individually. There was no templating, no automation just raw HTML, written line by line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Eleventy and Nunjucks, things are much easier. Content can be written in Markdown or Nunjucks templates, and Eleventy takes care of generating the final HTML. Instead of repeating the same structure on every page, layouts can be created and reused. Updates are simple--changing a single template regenerates the entire site. Data from JSON files or APIs can be pulled in to dynamically create pages. It&#39;s a much more efficient and flexible way to manage a static site compared to doing everything manually. And, the Eleventy RSS plugin automatically updates and processes an RSS feed whenever a new post is added.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ditching my Feedbin subscription</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/" />
    <updated>2025-02-20T15:15:40Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ditching-my-feedbin-subscription/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 20, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last three years, I’ve been using Feedbin as the RSS sync engine for Reeder, my go-to feed reader. But last year, I let my Feedbin subscription expire. I knew iCloud sync in Reeder was pretty shitty from past experience, but I was hoping it had gotten better. It hadn’t!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of dealing with iCloud sync’s painfully slow performance in Reeder, I decided to try NetNewsWire with iCloud sync instead. NetNewsWire’s iCloud sync was almost as fast if not as fast as Feedbin. But since I still wanted to use Reeder, I caved and renewed my Feedbin subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year though, I’m not doing that again. Paying $50 a year to use Reeder doesn’t make sense anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Feedbin renewal is coming up in a couple of months, and I’ve made up my mind I’m not renewing. So today, I updated my feeds in NetNewsWire and started using it full-time. That way, by the time my Feedbin subscription expires, I’ll be comfortable with the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more paying extra just to use one app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Capture, Process, Send</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/capture-process-send/" />
    <updated>2025-02-22T19:37:16Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/capture-process-send/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 22, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about this today so I wanted to share it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; is where I capture everything except to-do items, which I capture in &lt;a href=&quot;https://culturedcode.com/things/&quot;&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt;. Anything related to text, except code, is done in Drafts. Once I’ve finished writing, I&#39;ve created actions to send the text as a file to its final destination. Nothing remains in Drafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oj73vWw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Solving the BBEdit 15.1.4 Script Quarantine Issue</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/solving-the-bbedit-1514-script-quarantine-issue/" />
    <updated>2025-02-23T09:57:48Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/solving-the-bbedit-1514-script-quarantine-issue/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 23, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, if you&#39;re like me and use BBEdit, you might&#39;ve run into a weird error after the 15.1.4 update. Basically, your scripts suddenly stop working, and you get this message: &#39;This script file has been quarantined by macOS (application error code: 13312)&#39;. Super annoying. I reached out to BBEdit support, and they gave me the fix. I&#39;m sharing it here so you don&#39;t have to pull your hair out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made a change so that AppleScript execution, whether implicit (as in Startup Items or text factories) or explicit (via the Script menu or other UI invocation) will fail if the script file has been quarantined by macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OS will generally quarantine files that have been downloaded, but may do so for other reasons; there are various tools for correcting this, but the most straightforward is probably the &lt;code&gt;xattr&lt;/code&gt; command line tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following Terminal command will remove quarantine from any given file (use the actual File path rather than &amp;quot;/path/to/file&amp;quot;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;xattr -d com.apple.quarantine /path/to/file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in the release notes, but who reads the release notes. Obviously not me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prickly peril</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/prickly-peril/" />
    <updated>2025-02-24T17:33:15Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/prickly-peril/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a day warm enough to get outside. First on the agenda was trimming back those scraggly dead tree branches along the driveway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the challenge was the greenbrier. If you&#39;ve ever dealt with this, you know what I’m talking about. Common greenbrier is native to the eastern US, and it&#39;s made itself at home in our woodlands. They form dense, almost impenetrable thickets that take over everything. They have seriously sharp prickles. I learned that lesson despite wearing gloves. It&#39;s like botanical barbed wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I tackled a section of the thicket where our woodlands border the yard. It was a battle, to say the least. Cutting, pulling, and trying to avoid getting snagged by those fucking thorns. It&#39;s amazing how quickly this plant can take over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>