<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle>A blog by ldstephens.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/" />
  <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>ldstephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Zed fonts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/" />
    <updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 21, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you prefer mono fonts for writing and coding. I recently discovered a new mono-spaced font that you might be interested in. Macosguru &lt;a href=&quot;https://bicycleforyourmind.com/links%20of%20note%202025-01-21&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about a new text editor he found and also mentioned that the app’s default font, Zed mono, was clean and well-designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zed.dev/&quot;&gt;Zed&lt;/a&gt; is a new text editor which is built around the collaboration between humans and AI. I am not interested in that particular activity but it is an interesting addition to the world of text editors. It is snappy, clean, and modern. I don’t have a need for it, having immersed myself in Emacs. But if you are looking for an editor, I would give this a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about Zed. I loved the fonts that the editor uses as default. They have made them available.&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zed-industries/zed-fonts&quot;&gt;The Zed Mono and Sans typefaces, custom built from Iosevka&lt;/a&gt;. I can’t resist a free font, specially a well-designed, clean one. Get them to use in your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Macosguru, I’m not interested in Zed’s text editor, but I did download the mono fonts. I’m currently typing this in MarkEdit using the Zed mono-spaced font, and I like it. I’m going to use it for a while and see if it sticks for me. Check out the Zed editor and Zed fonts for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Intelligence and iPhone battery drain</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’ve recently noticed that my iPhone 15 Pro Max battery is draining faster than usual. I thought. Is this just me? Definitely not. &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.macrumors.com/threads/apple-intelligence-battery-drain.2442119/&quot;&gt;A lot of people&lt;/a&gt; are discussing this issue after enabling Apple Intelligence. For now, I’ve disabled it because I don’t find it particularly useful on my iPhone. After disabling Apple Intelligence my battery life is back to what it was before enabling it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You Can Build Your Own Static Blog - Here&#39;s How!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I bet a lot of you with a personal blog on platforms like Bear Blog, Pika, Write.as, have thought about building your own blog at some point. I know I was curious—until I finally decided to do for it! I didn’t have much knowledge of HTML or CSS, but I knew just enough to want to give it a shot. Plus, I figured I could use AI tools like ChatGPT or Claude to help me get started and tackle the stuff I didn’t know how to do. And the result? This blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve thought about creating your own blog too but felt overwhelmed by HTML, CSS, or all the technical details. Don’t worry, you’re not alone! The great news is that you can build a basic static blog site without needing a static site generator, the terminal, or advanced coding skills. With a little help from AI tools, it’s totally doable to create a site with an Atom feed for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down step by step. I’ve asked ChatGPT for assistance with this task. The final outcome is a very basic, static blog that serves as a step-by-step guide to help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Understand the Basics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving in, let’s get some quick definitions out of the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static site&lt;/strong&gt;: A website that doesn’t require a database or fancy backend. Think of it as a collection of simple HTML files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atom feed&lt;/strong&gt;: A type of RSS feed that allows people to subscribe to your blog and get updates when you post new content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be an expert at these. Just know that they’re essential to making a functional blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Pick the Right Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can do a lot of the heavy lifting for you. Here are some tools you’ll use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Code Generators&lt;/strong&gt;: Platforms like ChatGPT can generate the HTML, CSS, and Atom feed for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text Editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a simple editor like Visual Studio Code (free) to tweak the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting Service&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub Pages or Netlify are great free options for hosting your static blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Create the CSS File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by asking the AI to create a CSS file for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create a CSS stylesheet for a blog with a header, main content area, and a footer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what the AI might generate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;/* styles.css */
body {
   font-family: Arial, sans-serif;
   line-height: 1.6;
   margin: 0;
   padding: 0;
}

header {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   padding: 1rem 0;
   text-align: center;
}

main {
   padding: 2rem;
   max-width: 800px;
   margin: 0 auto;
}

footer {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   text-align: center;
   padding: 1rem 0;
}

nav a {
   margin: 0 1rem;
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

nav a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}

.blog-list {
   margin-top: 2rem;
}

.blog-list a {
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

.blog-list a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;styles.css&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Link the CSS File in Your HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, update your HTML files to reference the CSS file. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;My Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Welcome to My Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            This is the home page of my blog. Use the navigation to explore
            posts!
         &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the homepage for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Create the Blog Page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, ask the AI to generate a separate page for listing blog posts. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an HTML file for a blog page listing multiple posts with links to individual post pages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;section class=&amp;quot;blog-list&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Recent Posts&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post2.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 2&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post3.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 3&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the blog page for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6: Create Individual Blog Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each blog post, create a separate HTML file. Here’s an example for &lt;code&gt;post1.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;../styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;article&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the content of Post 1. Welcome to my first blog post!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/article&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place this file in a &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder (e.g., &lt;code&gt;blog/post1.html&lt;/code&gt;). Repeat for each new post, updating the links in &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 7: Create an Atom Feed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the AI to generate an Atom feed for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an Atom feed for a blog with multiple posts, each with its own link and publication date.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update the feed as needed when you add new posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 8: Host Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your files, it’s time to put them online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re using GitHub, create a new repository and upload your files. Go to the repository settings and enable GitHub Pages. Your blog will be live at &lt;code&gt;https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo-name/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netlify&lt;/strong&gt;: Drag and drop your files into Netlify, and it will instantly publish your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 9: Update Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you write a new post, you’ll need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new HTML file for the post in the &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link it to the &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt; page under the &amp;quot;Recent Posts&amp;quot; section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;code&gt;atom.xml&lt;/code&gt; feed with the new post details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the updated files to your hosting service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a static blog doesn’t have to be complicated. With AI tools to generate code and free hosting platforms to get your site online, you can create a functional blog. Once it’s live, you’ll have your space to share your thoughts with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Now I’m doing Yoga</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/" />
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 25, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, at 80, I like to think I’m pretty fit for my age. I’m 6 feet tall and weigh 165 pounds. Trix, our dog, and I walk 2 miles every single day, no exceptions. We’ve got a 10-acre property that keeps me plenty busy. In the winter, we heat the house with firewood I cut and split myself. I have a 35-ton log splitter that makes the job easier. Staying active is just who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I took a tumble down the basement stairs. Luckily I didn’t get hurt badly. A sore hip, sore back, and a gash on the palm of my left hand from attempting to catch myself. Oh yeah, my Apple Watch didn’t detect my fall. What the fuck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t my only fall over the last few years. As you age, poor balance becomes a concern, as the risk of falls increases. So with this last fall, Lisa insisted that I start doing Yoga that focuses on improving balance and core strength. So to get her off my back I agreed to start doing Yoga three times a week. Week one I realized how shitty my balance is. Week two I’m starting to see some slight improvement. Now on top of everything else that I do, I’m doing yoga three times a week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 29, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a bit of a rollercoaster when it came to my blog setup. I started the day with a plan after reading Herman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://herman.bearblog.dev/manifesto/&quot;&gt;Bear Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; post: move ldstephens back to Bearblog. This change would reduce the friction associated with posting to a static site, and Bearblog would provide me with built-in analytics. Seemed like a win-win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the afternoon, I tackled a necessary but tedious task in Bearblog—changing all the canonical links to alias and moved the DNS server setting to Bearblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, plot twist! By the evening, I decided to move ldstephens back to Netlify. At the end of the day, I just love that I built this site myself. There’s something satisfying about knowing it&#39;s mine, running on my own setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all that back and forth, I&#39;m right back where I started. But hey, sometimes you have to try something just to confirm that what you had was already the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>11ty project</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/" />
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 3, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to replicate this site in 11ty as a learning project. The first thing I did was install Node.js. When I came to the 11ty install step, the install failed. After some additional attempts, I determined the problem might be the version of Node.js that I installed. So I uninstalled Node.js. Today, I’ll install a different version and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop again</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 4, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to change the layout and design of this blog. Since it&#39;s a static site running on Netlify, making changes isn&#39;t always smooth. And, of course, I ended up breaking the fucking site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I had to point the DNS back to Bearblog, where I keep a duplicate version for moments like this when I inevitably mess up the static site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now (and maybe longer, depending on how things go), the blog is running on Bearblog until I get the new layout and design sorted.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop… again (but fixed now)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was fun. The new layout and design are finally done, and everything is back up and running on Netlify where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breaking the site (because, of course, I did), we’re back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Instapaper</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; was my go-to read-it-later app. Over the years it’s had a long and convoluted life some good and some not so good. During one of those not-so-good times, I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, Instapaper has been getting a lot of attention so every time the app gets updated I install it to test it out. Today I got an email from the developer announcing version 9.1 so I installed it and I’m using it in place for Goodlinks for the time being. One of the things that I like about Instapaper is the way it integrates with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reederapp.com/classic/&quot;&gt;Reeder Classic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll continue using Instapaper, but if I do, the free version is sufficient for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sleep Number vs. my snoring</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/" />
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 6, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently got a Sleep Number bed. I snore, which makes it difficult for Lisa to sleep. The bed has a snore setting that automatically adjusts its position to help reduce snoring. When activated, it gently raises the head of the bed by a few degrees to open airways and improve breathing. So when I snore, Lisa can adjust my side of the bed until I stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, when I woke up, I was surprised to find myself almost upright. Lisa said she kept adjusting the bed until I quit snoring–and that was the position when I finally stopped. At this rate, I might as well start sleeping in a recliner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the Sleep Number bed has been wonderful for my lower back.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>U.K. orders Apple to let it spy on users’ encrypted accounts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/" />
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 7, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/02/07/apple-encryption-backdoor-uk/&quot;&gt;Joseph Menn, The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security officials in the United Kingdom have demanded that Apple create a back door allowing them to retrieve all the content any Apple user worldwide has uploaded to the cloud.[…] The British government’s undisclosed order, issued last month, requires blanket capability to view fully encrypted material, not merely assistance in cracking a specific account, and has no known precedent in major democracies.[…] Rather than break the security promises it made to its users everywhere, Apple is likely to stop offering encrypted storage in the U.K., the people said. Yet that concession would not fulfill the U.K. demand for backdoor access to the service in other countries, including the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is fucking crazy shit! If there’s a backdoor, hackers and cybercriminals will eventually find a way in, putting our security and privacy at serious risk. Our personal data could be stolen, leading to identity theft, financial fraud, and other attacks. It wouldn’t just be law enforcement using it—bad actors, including hackers and even foreign governments, could exploit the same weakness, violating users’ right to privacy and secure communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple could pull iCloud from the UK</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/" />
    <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 9, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you who read my posts are in the U.K. You may have already read this. Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2025/02/07/could-apple-pull-icloud-services-from-uk/&quot;&gt;Tim Hardwick, MacRumors&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“A more dramatic response from Apple would involve completely removing iCloud services from the UK. While this would protect Apple&#39;s encryption standards, it would severely disrupt millions of UK users who rely on iCloud for photo storage, device backups, and document syncing. Users would need to find alternative cloud storage solutions and potentially lose access to years of accumulated data.”&lt;/em&gt; Are you concerned about this possibility?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cracked Corn 🌽</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/" />
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 10, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/QVy072ds.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeding time around here is no joke! We go through 100 pounds of cracked corn every week to keep the deer and wild turkeys happy as they wander our 10-acre property. Our place is actually a Certified Wildlife Habitat with the state of New Jersey, and we love all the creatures that call it home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we go through 40 pounds of birdseed for all the birds. Of course, the raccoon has figured out a little trick—every night, it climbs the tree, hangs off the bird feeder, and dumps the seed just so it can feast. Smart little guy! I haven’t spotted the groundhog yet this year, but I’m sure it’ll make an appearance soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On - Which HTML element are you [Quiz]?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 13, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James at James’ Coffee Blog created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/02/13/html-quiz&quot;&gt;fun quiz&lt;/a&gt; called “Which HTML element are you?” It has ten questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the quiz and “I’m the &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; element! You’re great at gathering ideas from different sources and putting them together”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>