<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>ldstephens</title>
  <subtitle>A blog by ldstephens.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://ldstephens.me/" />
  <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://ldstephens.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>ldstephens</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - The wonderful rabbit hole of BBEdit</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/" />
    <updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve used the free version of BBEdit starting back when the free version was TextWrangler. The only thing I used it for up to now was for the occasional time that I needed to write something in a plain text editor. When I decided to build a blog using html and css, I decided to pay for the full version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/&quot;&gt;BBEdit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://thejollyteapot.com/&quot;&gt;Nicolas Magand&lt;/a&gt;, now that I own the full version of BBEdit, I figured I should use it for writing markdown blog posts. Most markdown editors have keyboard shortcuts for bold, italic, and links, but not BBEdit. Since Nicolas switched from &lt;a href=&quot;https://thejollyteapot.com/2024/09/27/the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit&quot;&gt;MarkEdit to BBEdit&lt;/a&gt; I figured he must have figured something out for this. And, of course, he had:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can share with you a zip of the some of the script I have added to the Script folder of BBEdit, and now these actions are available in the Script menu, and therefore can be configured with a shortcut in the settings. I’ve recycled a few that I found online (from Dr Drang, Gruber, and more), and they work great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as he said, they work great! Now, in addition to building my blog in BBEdit, I can also write my blog posts. (Shit, I have to figure out how to end a sentence with double space for the period. That is a hard fucking habit to break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the help Nicolas!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If you&#39;re not already using an RSS reader you need to read this</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/if-youre-not-already-using-an-rss-reader-you-need-to-read-this/" />
    <updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/if-youre-not-already-using-an-rss-reader-you-need-to-read-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctorow in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2024/10/16/keep-it-really-simple-stupid/&quot;&gt;latest post&lt;/a&gt; on Pluralistic “You should be using an RSS reader” explains how RSS can help you reclaim your online experience from the enshittification of social media. He goes into detail on how RSS, or Really Simple Syndication, is a simple yet effective way to curate your own, ad-free feed of the web&#39;s best content. With an RSS reader, you can follow your favorite news sources, blogs, and even social media accounts, all in one place. No more endless scrolling through irrelevant content you see what you want, when you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I had a realization: the conduit through which I experience Molly&#39;s excellent work is totally enshittification-proof, and the more I use it, the easier it is for everyone to be less enshittified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conduit is anti-lock-in, it works for nearly the whole internet. It is surveillance-resistant, far more accessible than the web or any mobile app interface. It is my secret super-power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do your self a favor and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2024/10/16/keep-it-really-simple-stupid/&quot;&gt;read the article&lt;/a&gt; from start to finish. You’ll be glad you did.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update - BBEdit rabbit hole</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-bbedit-rabbit-hole/" />
    <updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-bbedit-rabbit-hole/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 24, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/re-the-wonderful-rabbit-hole-of-bbedit/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about the wonderful rabbit hole of BBEdit and how I now have it set for writing markdown except for one item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Shit, I have to figure out how to end a sentence with double space for the period. That is a hard fucking habit to break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got an email from MacOSX Guru suggesting that he does that with a Keyboard Maestro macro. I probably should have asked him for his macro, but instead, I attempted to create my own and was successful. The macro is triggered by double-tapping the spacebar which executes insert text &amp;quot;.&amp;quot; by typing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Canceling Optimum Internet Service? Good Luck!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/canceling-optimum-internet-service-good-luck/" />
    <updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/canceling-optimum-internet-service-good-luck/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 28, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I wrote about my experience with Optimum, our former internet service provider, and how we finally switched to Verizon FIOS. Today, Lisa called Optimum to cancel our old service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a fucking pain in the ass! They eventually processed the cancellation, but the hoops you have to jump through just to cancel should be illegal—and soon will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/10/federal-trade-commission-announces-final-click-cancel-rule-making-it-easier-consumers-end-recurring&quot;&gt;Federal Trade Commission Announces Final “Click-to-Cancel” Rule Making It Easier for Consumers to End Recurring Subscriptions and Memberships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Trade Commission today announced a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library/browse/federal-register-notices/negative-option-rule-final-rule&quot;&gt;final “click-to-cancel” rule&lt;/a&gt; that will require sellers to make it as easy for consumers to cancel their enrollment as it was to sign up. Most of the final rule’s provisions will go into effect 180 days after it is published in the Federal Register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Too often, businesses make people jump through endless hoops just to cancel a subscription,” said Commission Chair Lina M. Khan. “The FTC’s rule will end these tricks and traps, saving Americans time and money. Nobody should be stuck paying for a service they no longer want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commission’s updated rule will apply to almost all negative option programs in any media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Should I Migrate to a Static Site?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/should-i-migrate-to-a-static-site/" />
    <updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/should-i-migrate-to-a-static-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 28, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I&#39;ve become increasingly interested in static sites. This led me to learn some basic HTML and CSS with the goal of recreating my current Bearblog site (ldstephens) as a static site, potentially hosting it on GitHub Pages. I&#39;ve already completed building the new version, so the next step would be migrating all my existing posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major advantage of making this switch would be full ownership of my site, eliminating my dependency on Bearblog and its subscription. This would give me complete control over my content and hosting infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I&#39;m facing two main concerns about making this transition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSS Feed Impact&lt;/strong&gt;: My primary concern is that changing the RSS feed URL would cause me to lose my current RSS followers, who make up the core of my audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broken Links&lt;/strong&gt;: While all old links would break after the migration, this is less concerning since I no longer receive significant traffic from search results. My readership primarily comes through RSS subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d appreciate hearing from those who have undertaken similar migrations. What was your experience? How did you handle these challenges? Any insights would be valuable in helping me make this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>16GB for everyone - MacBook Air joins the RAM upgrade party</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/16gb-for-everyone-macbook-air-joins-the-ram-upgrade-party/" />
    <updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/16gb-for-everyone-macbook-air-joins-the-ram-upgrade-party/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on October 30, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time coming—Apple’s new Mac models and the MacBook Air now come with 16GB of RAM as standard, replacing the previous 8GB. I might have to consider upgrading from my M1 Air.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Intelligence first impressions</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-first-impressions/" />
    <updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-first-impressions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 2, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I tried Apple Intelligence on my iPhone, but honestly, I don’t see the point. The way I use my iPhone, it didn’t really add anything useful, and it seemed to drain the battery faster, so I turned it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve kept it turned on on my MacBook for now, but based on my early impressions, it’s still not on par with ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - On Maintaining Streaks</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-on-maintaining-streaks/" />
    <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-on-maintaining-streaks/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 3, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I participated in #100DaystoOffload and the longer it went on, the quality of my posts suffered. I stopped writing because I had something to say, instead, I wrote to keep the streak alive and in doing so I was doing myself and my readers a disservice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now approach things with “dailyish” in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandons-journal.com/re-on-maintaining-streaks/&quot;&gt;Brandon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This supports a point I was making in this opinion post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lstep.xyz/posts/blogging-challenges-are-they-really-worth-it/&quot;&gt;Blogging Challenges: Are They Really Worth It?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update - Static Site</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-static-site/" />
    <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/update-static-site/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 5, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a huge thank you to everyone who commented on my original post! After weighing the pros and cons, I&#39;ve decided that BearBlog is where I&#39;ll stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave building my static site a solid shot, creating it in raw HTML and CSS. But upkeep, adding new posts, and updating the feed.xml every time was just too tedious and error-prone. Sure, a static site generator could&#39;ve made things easier, but I found them too complex for me to fully get comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I learned a lot along the way, and it was absolutely worth the effort!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What’s Ahead for America Now?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-ahead-for-america-now/" />
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/whats-ahead-for-america-now/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 6, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to bed at my normal time last night. I didn&#39;t want to stay up and watch the election results come in. I expected a Harris win. I didn&#39;t want to be stressed watching the results come in. I figured I would just get the results when I woke up this morning. Harris didn&#39;t win. Trump won the electoral college and it&#39;s looking like the popular vote as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this election, the United States will become a different kind of country. We have a Republican-controlled Supreme Court, Senate, and perhaps the House as well. With that, the Republicans will be unconstrained with their agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big question is will we be better off or worse off after another four years of Trump?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPhone Notes Missing After Accepting New iCloud Terms? Here’s the Fix!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-notes-missing-after-accepting-new-icloud-terms-heres-the-fix/" />
    <updated>2024-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-notes-missing-after-accepting-new-icloud-terms-heres-the-fix/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 7, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, Apple recently updated their iCloud terms and conditions, and apparently, after accepting these new terms, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2024/11/07/how-to-fix-iphone-notes-disappearing/&quot;&gt;some iPhone users opened their Notes app to find all their notes gone&lt;/a&gt;! Luckily, I didn’t experience this myself, but some people are having this issue, and I wanted to share a simple fix to help you get those notes back if you’re one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Settings app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap your name at the top (Apple Account settings).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select iCloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap Notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Sync this iPhone is on (toggle it off and back on if it’s already enabled).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Notes app and wait a few minutes for your notes to reappear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Your next iPhone could cost $300 more in the Trump administration</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/your-next-iphone-could-cost-300-more-in-the-trump-administration/" />
    <updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/your-next-iphone-could-cost-300-more-in-the-trump-administration/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 8, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If President-elect &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/donald-trump/?itid=lk_inline_manual_2&quot;&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; follows through with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/16/trump-tariffs-impact-economy/&quot;&gt;sweeping new tariffs&lt;/a&gt; on anything made in China, your next iPhone could cost roughly $300 more, economists estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/11/08/apple-iphone-trump-tariffs-cost/&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Quietly Introduced iPhone Reboot Code Which is Locking Out Cops</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/" />
    <updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 10, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.404media.co/police-freak-out-at-iphones-mysteriously-rebooting-themselves-locking-cops-out/&quot;&gt;404 Media reported&lt;/a&gt; that law enforcement officials were freaking out that iPhones which had been stored for examination were mysteriously rebooting themselves. At the time the cause was unclear, with the officials only able to speculate why they were being locked out of the devices. Now a day later, the potential reason why is coming into view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Apple indeed added a feature called ‘inactivity reboot’ in iOS 18.1.,” Dr.-Ing. Jiska Classen, a research group leader at the Hasso Plattner Institute, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/naehrdine/status/1854896392797360484?ref=404media.co&quot;&gt;tweeted after 404 Media published&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday along with screenshots that they presented as the relevant pieces of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.404media.co/apple-quietly-introduced-iphone-reboot-code-which-is-locking-out-cops/&quot;&gt;Joseph Cox, 404 Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>reality is setting in</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/reality-is-setting-in/" />
    <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/reality-is-setting-in/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through my RSS feed this afternoon, I came across a 9to5 Mac post that said I could get an M3 MacBook Air with 16 GB of RAM and 256 storage for $899 at Amazon or Best Buy. That got my attention, and I thought I should take advantage of that price. It’s $400 off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting here and thinking about it now, reality is setting in. That new M3 Air won’t do anything that my M1 Air isn’t already doing for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Independent blogs lost in search</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/independent-blogs-lost-in-search/" />
    <updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/independent-blogs-lost-in-search/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 12, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been posting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.medium.com/&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; since 2015, and recently, I&#39;ve noticed a significant increase in views. This uptick seems to be related to Google&#39;s shift towards AI-powered search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&#39;s new search algorithm prioritizes content from platforms like Medium, Reddit, Stack Overflow, and Quora over traditional independent blogs. In the end, this trend is pretty fucking disheartening for independent bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like the unique, personal space of an independent blog is getting lost in the noise of the big platforms. For those of us who value independent blogging, it’s a frustrating reminder that the rules of visibility online keep shifting and not in our favor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2024-11-14 Blog update</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-14-blog-update/" />
    <updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-14-blog-update/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, as you know, I’ve been experimenting with a static site. As of today, this site is built entirely with &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmlforpeople.com/&quot;&gt;HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on Netlify. It has no complex server-side processing, databases, tracking scripts, cookies, or analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered using a static site generator but decided it wasn’t necessary for something this simple. Right now, it’s still in a testing phase. I want to make sure everything’s working smoothly, including the RSS feed. If I hit any issues, I might need to move back to Bearblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you spot anything off.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Bluesky? Mastodon? get your own blog instead</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/" />
    <updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 15, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this sudden rush to Bluesky and I have started to use it a little more but I keep coming down to the mindset you could just get your own blog instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ljpuk.net/2024/11/15/bluesky-mastodon-get-your-own-blog-instead/&quot;&gt;Lee Peterson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also noticed the rush to Bluesky, so I reactivated my account the other day to see what was happening. Today, I deactivated my account again. I just don’t get the point of social media. To me, it’s nonsensical (my opinion). It’s probably that I’m old school and would rather read your blog in my RSS feed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Colophon</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-16-colophon/" />
    <updated>2024-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-11-16-colophon/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, building this site has been a several-month project. I had a lot of stops and starts, but in the end, I persevered and it’s finally finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is built using static &lt;a href=&quot;https://htmlforpeople.com/&quot;&gt;HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; and is hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;. It automatically deploys when I commit changes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ldstep/ldstephens&quot;&gt;public GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding new posts, changing the design, or adding new features, that is done in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New posts are written in Markdown in &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; and copied as HTML to add to a new post in VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using AI to help you build your first static website</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/using-ai-to-help-you-build-your-first-static-website/" />
    <updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/using-ai-to-help-you-build-your-first-static-website/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 18, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a newcomer with little or no HTML or CSS experience, you&#39;re going to need guidance building your static site. While YouTube videos and Google searches offer fragmented advice, I found a more comprehensive approach using &lt;a href=&quot;https://claude.ai/new&quot;&gt;Claude AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claude helped me develop HTML and CSS templates. It provided accurate, actionable, and tailored advice that addressed my specific development needs. Claude transformed complex web development concepts into digestible, actionable steps. It also recommended using &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt; for coding and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for hosting and walked me through setting it up via GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do the same thing with ChatGPT but I found Claude to be more precise and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mac tip - navigating and selecting text from the keyboard</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-navigating-and-selecting-text-from-the-keyboard/" />
    <updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/mac-tip-navigating-and-selecting-text-from-the-keyboard/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 20, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I have Gary’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://macmost.com/&quot;&gt;MacMost Mac Video Tutorials and Tips&lt;/a&gt; in my RSS feed and the other day I saved this video &lt;a href=&quot;https://macmost.com/10-things-you-didnt-know-you-could-do-with-just-the-keyboard.html&quot;&gt;10 Things You Didn’t Know You Could Do With Just the Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; in Goodlinks to watch later. Well, I finally got around to watching it. By the way, if you love the Mac, MacMost is a great resource for tons of tutorials on how to use your Mac better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video highlights hidden macOS tricks for text navigation and selection using the keyboard. Here’s the gist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the arrow keys to move the text cursor back and forth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold the &lt;strong&gt;Shift key&lt;/strong&gt; while using the arrow keys to select text:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Right Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; selects one character at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can type, replace, or paste over the selected text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;strong&gt;Option key&lt;/strong&gt; for word-based movement:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option + Right/Left Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; jumps by word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select one word at a time (&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Option + Right/Left Arrow&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;strong&gt;Up/Down Arrow keys&lt;/strong&gt; to navigate vertically:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select text while moving up or down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option + Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; jumps by paragraph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt; to select paragraphs (&lt;strong&gt;Shift + Option + Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt;), and use &lt;strong&gt;Down Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; repeatedly to select multiple paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out, you’ll probably pick up a few new tricks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - The App Store era must end, and the Mac is the model</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-app-store-era-must-end-and-the-mac-is-the-model/" />
    <updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-the-app-store-era-must-end-and-the-mac-is-the-model/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his Macworld article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macworld.com/article/2525708&quot;&gt;Jason Snell&lt;/a&gt; makes a strong argument for why the Mac’s software ecosystem should be the model for iOS and iPadOS. Unlike iOS’s strict, App Store-only model, macOS has a more flexible approach to software distribution that has a balance between security and user freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App Store Apps: These are the most secure and Apple-approved, meeting strict standards. Macs can even be set to run only these apps, but it’s not the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notarized Apps: Developers can distribute apps outside the App Store by submitting them for an automated Apple scan. These apps are safer than fully unverified software, as Apple’s cryptographic signature ensures they’re untampered and from known developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Notarized Apps: These come with no Apple oversight, often from open-source or niche developers. While less secure, they’re still an option for users willing to take the risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system would let iOS and iPadOS users choose what they want without putting their safety at risk, just like Apple does on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cancel a drag and drop on Mac</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cancel-a-drag-and-drop-on-mac/" />
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cancel-a-drag-and-drop-on-mac/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 23, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking this morning and listening to ATP episode 614, the subject of how to cancel a drag and drop came up again. Of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypercritical.co/about/&quot;&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt; knew the answer. I didn’t. I was glad to learn the answer because there have been times that I have started a drag and drop to move files to a different folder, and for some reason, it gets fucked up (user error missing the target folder), and I always panic and want to end the drag and drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to John, all you need to do is &lt;strong&gt;use the escape key&lt;/strong&gt;. I tested it and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, John!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To POSSE or not to POSSE</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/to-posse-or-not-to-posse/" />
    <updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/to-posse-or-not-to-posse/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 25, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt;? It stands for &amp;quot;Publish on your Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere&amp;quot; - basically where you post stuff on your site first, then share it around on social media and whatnot, always linking back to your original post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I&#39;ve been wondering if I should be doing this. And for me, it&#39;s clearly no. Since I don&#39;t use social media, why would I want to put my blog posts there? Sure, maybe I&#39;d pick up a few more RSS subscribers, but that&#39;s not why I&#39;m blogging in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is its own thing. It’s mainly just a place to get my thoughts out there. My RSS followers are my people, and I pick up new ones now and then when other bloggers link to something I wrote. And that’s perfectly fine with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sticking My Head in the Sand (But Not Really)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/sticking-my-head-in-the-sand-but-not-really/" />
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/sticking-my-head-in-the-sand-but-not-really/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on November 26, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent way too much time over the last 12 months paying way too much &lt;em&gt;fucking&lt;/em&gt; attention to political news. The US election is over. I’m over it. I’ve purged all news from my RSS feed, including any blogs that can’t resist regularly interjecting politics into their content. Gone. Done. Also? No more 24-hour news channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m old. I want to enjoy what’s left of this ride. I don’t want to spend my final years fretting about everything that’s coming down the pike that I don’t agree with. Do I care? Hell yes, I care. But let’s be real, there’s nothing I can do to change it. And let’s face it, nobody’s going to be thrilled with everything that’s coming anyway, no matter who you voted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, am I sticking my head in the sand? Nope. I’m still watching the national news on broadcast TV, you know, the regular stuff that gives me what I need to know without dragging me into the political abyss. I’ll stay informed, but the days of letting politics hijack my fucking sanity are over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - My advice to iPhone users considering a move to Android</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/" />
    <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 1, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed that some bloggers I follow are switching from iOS to Android. I’m sure each of them has their reasons for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved from Android to iOS 10 years ago. Android has probably changed a lot since then, but I don’t see myself ever returning. I left Android because I wanted to stop using Google services. In addition, iOS offered better security and privacy, and consistent OS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://merecivilian.com/my-advice-to-iphone-users-considering-a-move-to-android/&quot;&gt;MereCivilian&lt;/a&gt; recently switched to Android and offers some good advice for those who may be considering the switch. As I mentioned above, I stopped using Google services long ago and wouldn’t want to start again, which would be necessary with an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Switching blogging engines</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/switching-blogging-engines/" />
    <updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/switching-blogging-engines/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 3, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just read Jack Bay’s post &lt;a href=&quot;https://baty.net/2024/12/from-hugo-to-ghost-and-back-again/&quot;&gt;From Hugo to Ghost and back again&lt;/a&gt; about how often he switches up his blogging engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hear you all giggling. Ha ha very funny, Jack changed his blog again. I get it. Most normal people don’t change blogging engines every month or two.[…] Also, and maybe most importantly, I prefer static websites. The arguments in favor of static websites are enough, but they aren’t why I want a static site. It &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; better having a static website. The actual publishing part can be a pain in the ass (:::cough::, Hugo) but the results are worth it. A folder full of HTML files and some images, starting on my local drive and synced to a simple web server…mmmmm, yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me a bit of myself. You may have noticed that after switching this blog to a static site, I’ve moved it back to Bearblog and then back to static a couple of times over the last few weeks. Much like Jack, it just feels better to have a static website. I take pride in something I’ve built, and my content isn’t locked inside Bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I agree – publishing with a static site is a pain in the ass, but it’s worth the extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stop the constant switching, I decided to close my Bear account. In the end, this entire site is just a folder full of HTML files on my SSD, synced to GitHub and hosted on Netlify.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drafts - the best $20 bucks I spend every year</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-the-best-20-bucks-i-spend-every-year/" />
    <updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/drafts-the-best-20-bucks-i-spend-every-year/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 7, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I want to give a shout-out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://getdrafts.com/&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;! It’s the best $20 bucks I spend every year. I first installed Drafts in 2014, when it was only available on iOS. Then, in 2019, Drafts came to the Mac. Drafts is my all-time favorite app and is where every bit of text starts: blog ideas, random thoughts, notes, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have an idea or a thought, I immediately open Drafts and save it. It’s my go-to for quick note-taking. I use it to outline, draft, and format all my blog posts in Markdown. I keep everything organized with tags and workspaces. It’s also my personal information dump; with its amazing search, Drafts serves as my central repository for all the random bits of info I collect. On top of that, I’ve set up custom actions that let me do just about anything with my text: sending it to other apps, emailing it, saving it as a file, formatting it, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never tried Drafts, you gotta give it a try. There’s a free version to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Thoughts On Mangione</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-thoughts-on-mangione/" />
    <updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-thoughts-on-mangione/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Post December 11, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about the state of healthcare in America in light of the murder of the United Healthcare CEO. I have hesitated writing about how I feel about this situation, but this morning, I read Dave Rogers, Nice Marmot &lt;a href=&quot;https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2024/December_2024.html#note_2570&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about this very subject, so I thought I would say what I’m thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t given a great deal of thought to how I feel about the murder of that CEO. (I’m not mentioning his name mostly because I can’t recall it at the moment; but also because I don’t think he’s worthy of _“Say his name!”_respect.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trae Crowder is a stand-up comedian who has a YouTube channel called Liberal Redneck. I watch his videos because I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a laugh, and his are funny but also intelligent. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/aUcwZTWv2PY?si=ko0YNmGuWEo1KQfm&quot;&gt;I found this one particularly thought provoking&lt;/a&gt;, which is significant because I’d been kind of going out of my way &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to think about it. My reaction is that I don’t find much to disagree with in his comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before reading Dave’s post, I read a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-lede/what-the-murder-of-the-unitedhealthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-means-to-america&quot;&gt;New Yorker article&lt;/a&gt; by Jia Tolentino, “What the Murder of the United Healthcare C.E.O. Means to America&amp;quot; and I wanted to point out that United Healthcare denies 32% of insurance claims. Yep, nearly a third of claims submitted to this company are denied. That’s double the industry average, according to The New Yorker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Yorker quoted a person who posted on Reddit’s r/nurses forum, whose profile describes her as an I.C.U. nurse, wrote, &amp;quot;Honestly, I’m not wishing anyone harm, but when you’ve spent so much time and made so much money by increasing the suffering of the humanity around you, it’s hard for me to summon empathy that you died”. Thompson, who became C.E.O. in 2021, had raised annual profits from twelve billion dollars to sixteen billion dollars during his tenure. He received more than ten million dollars in compensation last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denying people the care they desperately need is fucking wrong and cruel. Yet, this level of corporate-driven harm has become so normalized in America that we barely blink at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m conflicted about the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Digital responsibilities</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-digital-responsibilities/" />
    <updated>2024-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-digital-responsibilities/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 14, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&quot;https://manuelmoreale.com/digital-responsibilities&quot;&gt;Manu&#39;s blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a post going viral on Hacker News. After being shared on Hacker News by someone, his website experienced a massive traffic spike that would make most website owners nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What caught my attention wasn&#39;t just the traffic surge but Manu&#39;s reflections on the broader question of online content sharing and the potential impact of sending unexpected waves of internet traffic to someone&#39;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I’m wondering, if my site was big enough to cause problems, would then be my responsibility to be careful what I link to? Or should I just assume that other people out there know what they’re doing and I can keep linking without a second thought? My gut reaction tells me that it’s not really my responsibility to worry about the way other people run their sites but maybe I’m wrong and I should worry about that. &lt;strong&gt;I’d love to know what you think because this is one of those situations where I can see good arguments on both sides.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ldstephens is a static site that runs on Netlify’s Free Plan. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 GB monthly bandwidth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 GB storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progressive usage notifications at 50%, 75%, 90%, and 100% of monthly limits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic site suspension if monthly limits are exceeded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick upgrade option to continue site availability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see a Hacker News viral moment could use up 100 GB of bandwidth fairly easily and could potentially suspend my site until the next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what Manu is asking is how I would feel if he shared one of my posts and it, for some reason, went viral and, exceeded my bandwidth limit and knocked my site offline. Would I feel that he had any responsibility? My answer is no. It’s my responsibility to manage my site, and he is welcome to share anything that I write, just as I’m sharing what he wrote in this post and responding to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>App Defaults</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-12-24-app-defaults/" />
    <updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/2024-12-24-app-defaults/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 16, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated December 15, 2024: Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://defaults.rknight.me/&quot;&gt;Hemispheric Views 097 - Duel of the Defaults&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Client: Mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail Server: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmail.com/?STKI=14726057&quot;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes: Drafts, Apple Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-Do: GoodTask/Reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone Photo Shooting: iOS Camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo Management: Photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar: Fantastical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud File Storage: iCloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS: Reeder Classic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacts: Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser: Safari, Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat: Messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bookmarks: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read It Later: Goodlinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading: Kindle Paperwhite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcast: Overcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text: Drafts, iA Writer, VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launcher: Alfred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spreadsheets: Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shopping Lists: Reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts: Overcast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password Management: Bitwarden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather: Carrot Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple&#39;s unwanted 18.2 Mail makeover</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover/" />
    <updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 21, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated my iPhone to iOS 18.2 the other day and was pissed to find my Mail app hijacked by the categories and giant sender icons. I was more pissed that the update just forced these changes on me without even asking if I wanted these shitty&lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-unwanted-182-mail-makeover#fn:1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After fucking around for a while, I figured out how to turn these annoying new features off and return to the Mail interface that’s worked perfectly fine forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable sender icons, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Settings app on your iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down and tap “Apps”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find and tap “Mail”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locate the “Message List” section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle off the switch next to “Show Contact Photos”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable categories, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Mail app on your iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap the “More” button (three dots) in the upper right corner of your inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “List View” from the pop-up menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>People don’t give a shit about Vision Pro</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/people-dont-give-a-shit-about-vision-pro/" />
    <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/people-dont-give-a-shit-about-vision-pro/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on December 27, 2024 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in January, I wrote a post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/apples-vision-pro-who-actually-gives-a-shit&quot;&gt;Apple’s Vision Pro: Who actually gives a shit?&lt;/a&gt;. “Vision Pro? Who gives a shit, right? That’s probably what most folks on the sidewalk would say. And honestly, I get it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Lisa and I we went to the Apple store to buy her a new iPhone. It was my Christmas present to her. We traded in an iPhone 11 and purchased an iPhone 16 Pro. Considering the size of the crowd in the store, we were there for a little over two hours. That included purchasing the new phone, processing the trade-in, and the setting up of the new phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vision Pro had its own table in the back corner of the store. I was keeping my eye on it because I was curious if anyone would go over and check it out. In the two-plus hours that we were in the store, not one person went to the table to check out the Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was right. People just don’t give a shit about the Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Year 2025</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/new-year-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/new-year-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 1, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are again - another year has flown by! They seem to go by faster and faster, and 2024 was no exception. It’s hard to believe we’re already in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m not one to dwell too much on the past, I will say that 2024 was a good year for Lisa and me. Looking ahead, my hope for 2025 is to continue living a healthy lifestyle and making the most of each day. I’ve got a couple of significant milestones coming up this year, which I’ll likely share more about when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year, and thank you for being a reader!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I don’t care about your politics</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/" />
    <updated>2025-01-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samhawken.com/i-dont-care-about-your-politics/&quot;&gt;Sam Hawken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a long-standing position on politics: don’t make your politics my problem, and I won’t let mine become yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that I don’t have strong political feelings because I do, but I am saying that I’m not interested in discussing that topic with anyone I wouldn’t hug. This seems to be the healthiest approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether I agree with or disagree with your politics, I don’t want to read about them. If you must write about them, I’ll remove you from my RSS feed. I agree with Sam. We all have political views, and as divided as we are over those views, the healthiest approach is to not fucking discuss them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I’ve been doing it wrong</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/" />
    <updated>2025-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 6, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using GitHub all wrong for this site. Instead of working from a cloned repository, I was just using a regular folder of files on my computer. Whenever I wanted to add a new post or make changes, I’d edit them in VS Code, then drag and drop the updated files directly into GitHub’s web interface. I knew this wasn’t the right way to do it, but I didn’t know any better. So, I started searching YouTube for a better way to handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iv8rSLsi1xo&quot;&gt;GitHub Tutorial - Beginner’s Training Guide - YouTube&lt;/a&gt; that helped immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I needed to do was install GitHub Desktop and I needed to clone the repository locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now GitHub Desktop connects GitHub, my local repository, and VS Code together. Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting to GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub Desktop links directly to my GitHub account, so I can easily clone repositories and sync my changes with the remote repositories on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing My Local Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: When I clone a repository using GitHub Desktop, it creates a local copy on my computer. This is where I make changes and commit updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Visual Studio Code (VS Code)&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve set VS Code as my default editor in GitHub Desktop. When I click “Open in Visual Studio Code,” it opens my local repository in VS Code, ready for me to start coding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping Everything in Sync&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write and edit my code in &lt;strong&gt;VS Code&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Desktop tracks the changes I make and lets me commit them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I’ve committed, I can push my changes to GitHub or pull updates from the remote repository when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, taking the time to learn GitHub Desktop has made managing my static site so much easier. I can jump into VS Code to edit, track changes locally, and sync it all with GitHub in just a couple of clicks. It’s been a fucking game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ldstephens - notes</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-notes/" />
    <updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/ldstephens-notes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 7, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I have now added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/notes&quot;&gt;notes page&lt;/a&gt; to the blog. Notes are shorter random posts, kinda like a microblog or what I would post on social media if I used social media, which I don’t. Notes include link posts as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Send articles from iPhone to Kindle for reading later</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later/" />
    <updated>2025-01-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 9, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I saved an article to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt; to read later. Today I decided to read it and discovered that the article is a 33 minute read. I didn’t want to take the time to read it right then, I thought that’s something that I would like to read on my Kindle Paperwhite while I’m in bed this evening&lt;a href=&quot;https://ldstephens.me/posts/send-articles-from-iphone-to-kindle-for-reading-later#fn1-27410&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. The next question is how the hell do I get this article on my Kindle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was easy. I opened the article on my iPhone and saved it to my Kindle via the share sheet save to Kindle. I wrote this to share a helpful tip I didn’t know about myself. If you’re interested in doing the same thing, I hope you find it useful!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Social networking alternatives for the Meta- and Musk-averse</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-social-networking-alternatives-for-the-/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-social-networking-alternatives-for-the-/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 10, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/23429095/twitter-social-network-alternatives-mastodon-reddit-tumblr-cohost&quot;&gt;Verge article&lt;/a&gt; in my RSS feed about alternatives for the Meta- and Musk-averse and wondered if blogging was provided as an alternative. Well, you probably guessed blogging was not provided as an alternative—just more social media platforms. Look folks maybe it’s time to quit social media and start a blog. If what you’re using isn’t already enshittified it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>iPhone one screen setup</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-one-screen-setup/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/iphone-one-screen-setup/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 13, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, For the new year, I decided to clean up my iPhone&#39;s Home screen. While I&#39;ve been using just one screen for a while now, I wanted to give it a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I removed all apps from my Home screen except for those in the Dock. My plan was to only add back the apps I use most often. For everything else, I can just use Spotlight search or App Library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my Home Screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tmjrAb7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What happens on your device, stays on your device – until it doesn’t</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 15, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://decoding.io/2025/01/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/&quot;&gt;Zsolt Benke&lt;/a&gt; for sharing this post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.obdev.at/blog/what-happens-on-your-device-stays-on-your-device-until-it-doesnt/&quot;&gt;Objective Development Blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;macOS Sequoia introduces another new feature labelled Help Apple Improve Search, which sends and stores various search queries from Safari, Spotlight, and other sources to improve search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature, too, is enabled by default and is well hidden at the very bottom of System Settings &amp;gt; Spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that I had disabled this setting on my iPhone, and iPad but not on my Mac so I disabled it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Celebrated Lawyer ‘Fires’ Meta As A Client Over Zuck’s ‘Neo-Nazi Madness’</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 16, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2025/01/15/celebrated-lawyer-fires-meta-as-a-client-over-zucks-neo-nazi-madness/&quot;&gt;Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And earlier this week, he announced that he has “&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/marklemley.bsky.social/post/3lfnpmxtam22r&quot;&gt;fired Meta as a client&lt;/a&gt;.” Lemley was representing Meta in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/2023/07/11/a-bunch-of-authors-sue-openai-claiming-copyright-infringement-because-they-dont-understand-copyright/&quot;&gt;Kadrey v. Meta lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; regarding Meta’s use of books in training its AI. And, as the docket shows, on Monday, he withdrew as an attorney for Meta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Lemley noted on various social media profiles, he cannot stomach what he sees as Zuckerberg’s embrace of nonsense and this is how he is responding to “Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook’s descent into toxic masculinity and Neo-Nazi madness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👏👏👏&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>James’ Coffee Blog</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/james-coffee-blog/" />
    <updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/james-coffee-blog/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 17, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, the other day, I was reading a blog post (wish I could remember whose!) about the indie web. It had several links, and I clicked one that took me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;indieweb.org&lt;/a&gt;. While browsing there, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/&quot;&gt;James’ Coffee Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really hooked me was James’ content. It’s a mix of tech and personal topics. I spent some time exploring his site and found tons of interesting articles to dive into. Needless to say, James’ Coffee Blog is now part of my RSS feed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not already following James, check out his site. I think you’ll find it worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that I highlighted while reading one of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/01/15/static-dynamic/&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a static site is significant to me because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static sites are fast (when engineered with performance in mind, of course!0. There is a significantly reduced admin tax. If my publishing tool goes down for any reason, my static site can still be available. I enjoy having folders of text files to edit: both markdown for posts and HTML for templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t agree more, static sites offer speed, simplicity, and the satisfaction of working directly with text files!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Don’t forget your RSS readers</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/dont-forget-your-rss-readers/" />
    <updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/dont-forget-your-rss-readers/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 18, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking analytics for ldstephens, it appears to receive relatively few direct page views. This can sometimes be discouraging. However, I must keep in mind that my target audience isn’t solely comprised of direct visitors but rather the 360+ RSS followers who are most likely to read my posts through their RSS reader app.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re - Zed fonts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/" />
    <updated>2025-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/re-zed-fonts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 21, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you prefer mono fonts for writing and coding. I recently discovered a new mono-spaced font that you might be interested in. Macosguru &lt;a href=&quot;https://bicycleforyourmind.com/links%20of%20note%202025-01-21&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about a new text editor he found and also mentioned that the app’s default font, Zed mono, was clean and well-designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zed.dev/&quot;&gt;Zed&lt;/a&gt; is a new text editor which is built around the collaboration between humans and AI. I am not interested in that particular activity but it is an interesting addition to the world of text editors. It is snappy, clean, and modern. I don’t have a need for it, having immersed myself in Emacs. But if you are looking for an editor, I would give this a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about Zed. I loved the fonts that the editor uses as default. They have made them available.&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zed-industries/zed-fonts&quot;&gt;The Zed Mono and Sans typefaces, custom built from Iosevka&lt;/a&gt;. I can’t resist a free font, specially a well-designed, clean one. Get them to use in your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Macosguru, I’m not interested in Zed’s text editor, but I did download the mono fonts. I’m currently typing this in MarkEdit using the Zed mono-spaced font, and I like it. I’m going to use it for a while and see if it sticks for me. Check out the Zed editor and Zed fonts for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Intelligence and iPhone battery drain</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-intelligence-iphone-battery-drain/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’ve recently noticed that my iPhone 15 Pro Max battery is draining faster than usual. I thought. Is this just me? Definitely not. &lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.macrumors.com/threads/apple-intelligence-battery-drain.2442119/&quot;&gt;A lot of people&lt;/a&gt; are discussing this issue after enabling Apple Intelligence. For now, I’ve disabled it because I don’t find it particularly useful on my iPhone. After disabling Apple Intelligence my battery life is back to what it was before enabling it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You Can Build Your Own Static Blog - Here&#39;s How!</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/" />
    <updated>2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/you-can-build-your-own-static-blog-heres-how/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 24, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I bet a lot of you with a personal blog on platforms like Bear Blog, Pika, Write.as, have thought about building your own blog at some point. I know I was curious—until I finally decided to do for it! I didn’t have much knowledge of HTML or CSS, but I knew just enough to want to give it a shot. Plus, I figured I could use AI tools like ChatGPT or Claude to help me get started and tackle the stuff I didn’t know how to do. And the result? This blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve thought about creating your own blog too but felt overwhelmed by HTML, CSS, or all the technical details. Don’t worry, you’re not alone! The great news is that you can build a basic static blog site without needing a static site generator, the terminal, or advanced coding skills. With a little help from AI tools, it’s totally doable to create a site with an Atom feed for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down step by step. I’ve asked ChatGPT for assistance with this task. The final outcome is a very basic, static blog that serves as a step-by-step guide to help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Understand the Basics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving in, let’s get some quick definitions out of the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static site&lt;/strong&gt;: A website that doesn’t require a database or fancy backend. Think of it as a collection of simple HTML files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atom feed&lt;/strong&gt;: A type of RSS feed that allows people to subscribe to your blog and get updates when you post new content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be an expert at these. Just know that they’re essential to making a functional blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Pick the Right Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can do a lot of the heavy lifting for you. Here are some tools you’ll use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Code Generators&lt;/strong&gt;: Platforms like ChatGPT can generate the HTML, CSS, and Atom feed for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text Editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Use a simple editor like Visual Studio Code (free) to tweak the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting Service&lt;/strong&gt;: GitHub Pages or Netlify are great free options for hosting your static blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Create the CSS File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by asking the AI to create a CSS file for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create a CSS stylesheet for a blog with a header, main content area, and a footer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what the AI might generate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;/* styles.css */
body {
   font-family: Arial, sans-serif;
   line-height: 1.6;
   margin: 0;
   padding: 0;
}

header {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   padding: 1rem 0;
   text-align: center;
}

main {
   padding: 2rem;
   max-width: 800px;
   margin: 0 auto;
}

footer {
   background: #333;
   color: #fff;
   text-align: center;
   padding: 1rem 0;
}

nav a {
   margin: 0 1rem;
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

nav a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}

.blog-list {
   margin-top: 2rem;
}

.blog-list a {
   text-decoration: none;
   color: #007bff;
}

.blog-list a:hover {
   text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;styles.css&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Link the CSS File in Your HTML&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, update your HTML files to reference the CSS file. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;My Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Welcome to My Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
            This is the home page of my blog. Use the navigation to explore
            posts!
         &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the homepage for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Create the Blog Page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, ask the AI to generate a separate page for listing blog posts. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an HTML file for a blog page listing multiple posts with links to individual post pages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;section class=&amp;quot;blog-list&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;Recent Posts&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post2.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 2&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
               &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;blog/post3.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post 3&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this file as &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;. It will serve as the blog page for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 6: Create Individual Blog Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each blog post, create a separate HTML file. Here’s an example for &lt;code&gt;post1.html&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;../styles.css&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;header&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Post 1&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Home&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;../blog.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Blog&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;article&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is the content of Post 1. Welcome to my first blog post!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;/article&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;amp;copy; 2025 My Blog&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/footer&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place this file in a &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder (e.g., &lt;code&gt;blog/post1.html&lt;/code&gt;). Repeat for each new post, updating the links in &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 7: Create an Atom Feed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask the AI to generate an Atom feed for your blog. Use this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Create an Atom feed for a blog with multiple posts, each with its own link and publication date.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update the feed as needed when you add new posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 8: Host Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your files, it’s time to put them online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/strong&gt;: If you’re using GitHub, create a new repository and upload your files. Go to the repository settings and enable GitHub Pages. Your blog will be live at &lt;code&gt;https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo-name/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netlify&lt;/strong&gt;: Drag and drop your files into Netlify, and it will instantly publish your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 9: Update Your Blog&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you write a new post, you’ll need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new HTML file for the post in the &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link it to the &lt;code&gt;blog.html&lt;/code&gt; page under the &amp;quot;Recent Posts&amp;quot; section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;code&gt;atom.xml&lt;/code&gt; feed with the new post details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the updated files to your hosting service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a static blog doesn’t have to be complicated. With AI tools to generate code and free hosting platforms to get your site online, you can create a functional blog. Once it’s live, you’ll have your space to share your thoughts with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Now I’m doing Yoga</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/" />
    <updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/now-im-doing-yoga/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 25, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, at 80, I like to think I’m pretty fit for my age. I’m 6 feet tall and weigh 165 pounds. Trix, our dog, and I walk 2 miles every single day, no exceptions. We’ve got a 10-acre property that keeps me plenty busy. In the winter, we heat the house with firewood I cut and split myself. I have a 35-ton log splitter that makes the job easier. Staying active is just who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I took a tumble down the basement stairs. Luckily I didn’t get hurt badly. A sore hip, sore back, and a gash on the palm of my left hand from attempting to catch myself. Oh yeah, my Apple Watch didn’t detect my fall. What the fuck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t my only fall over the last few years. As you age, poor balance becomes a concern, as the risk of falls increases. So with this last fall, Lisa insisted that I start doing Yoga that focuses on improving balance and core strength. So to get her off my back I agreed to start doing Yoga three times a week. Week one I realized how shitty my balance is. Week two I’m starting to see some slight improvement. Now on top of everything else that I do, I’m doing yoga three times a week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on January 29, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a bit of a rollercoaster when it came to my blog setup. I started the day with a plan after reading Herman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://herman.bearblog.dev/manifesto/&quot;&gt;Bear Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; post: move ldstephens back to Bearblog. This change would reduce the friction associated with posting to a static site, and Bearblog would provide me with built-in analytics. Seemed like a win-win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the afternoon, I tackled a necessary but tedious task in Bearblog—changing all the canonical links to alias and moved the DNS server setting to Bearblog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, plot twist! By the evening, I decided to move ldstephens back to Netlify. At the end of the day, I just love that I built this site myself. There’s something satisfying about knowing it&#39;s mine, running on my own setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after all that back and forth, I&#39;m right back where I started. But hey, sometimes you have to try something just to confirm that what you had was already the best fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>11ty project</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/" />
    <updated>2025-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/11ty-project/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 3, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to replicate this site in 11ty as a learning project. The first thing I did was install Node.js. When I came to the 11ty install step, the install failed. After some additional attempts, I determined the problem might be the version of Node.js that I installed. So I uninstalled Node.js. Today, I’ll install a different version and start over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop again</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 4, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I decided to change the layout and design of this blog. Since it&#39;s a static site running on Netlify, making changes isn&#39;t always smooth. And, of course, I ended up breaking the fucking site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I had to point the DNS back to Bearblog, where I keep a duplicate version for moments like this when I inevitably mess up the static site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now (and maybe longer, depending on how things go), the blog is running on Bearblog until I get the new layout and design sorted.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog setup flip-flop… again (but fixed now)</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/blog-setup-flip-flop-again-but-fixed-now/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was fun. The new layout and design are finally done, and everything is back up and running on Netlify where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breaking the site (because, of course, I did), we’re back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Instapaper</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/" />
    <updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/instapaper/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 5, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; was my go-to read-it-later app. Over the years it’s had a long and convoluted life some good and some not so good. During one of those not-so-good times, I switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodlinks.app/&quot;&gt;Goodlinks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, Instapaper has been getting a lot of attention so every time the app gets updated I install it to test it out. Today I got an email from the developer announcing version 9.1 so I installed it and I’m using it in place for Goodlinks for the time being. One of the things that I like about Instapaper is the way it integrates with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reederapp.com/classic/&quot;&gt;Reeder Classic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll continue using Instapaper, but if I do, the free version is sufficient for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sleep Number vs. my snoring</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/" />
    <updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/sleep-number-vs-my-snoring/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 6, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently got a Sleep Number bed. I snore, which makes it difficult for Lisa to sleep. The bed has a snore setting that automatically adjusts its position to help reduce snoring. When activated, it gently raises the head of the bed by a few degrees to open airways and improve breathing. So when I snore, Lisa can adjust my side of the bed until I stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, when I woke up, I was surprised to find myself almost upright. Lisa said she kept adjusting the bed until I quit snoring–and that was the position when I finally stopped. At this rate, I might as well start sleeping in a recliner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the Sleep Number bed has been wonderful for my lower back.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>U.K. orders Apple to let it spy on users’ encrypted accounts</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/" />
    <updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/uk-orders-apple-to-let-it-spy-on-users-encrypted-accounts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 7, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/02/07/apple-encryption-backdoor-uk/&quot;&gt;Joseph Menn, The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security officials in the United Kingdom have demanded that Apple create a back door allowing them to retrieve all the content any Apple user worldwide has uploaded to the cloud.[…] The British government’s undisclosed order, issued last month, requires blanket capability to view fully encrypted material, not merely assistance in cracking a specific account, and has no known precedent in major democracies.[…] Rather than break the security promises it made to its users everywhere, Apple is likely to stop offering encrypted storage in the U.K., the people said. Yet that concession would not fulfill the U.K. demand for backdoor access to the service in other countries, including the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is fucking crazy shit! If there’s a backdoor, hackers and cybercriminals will eventually find a way in, putting our security and privacy at serious risk. Our personal data could be stolen, leading to identity theft, financial fraud, and other attacks. It wouldn’t just be law enforcement using it—bad actors, including hackers and even foreign governments, could exploit the same weakness, violating users’ right to privacy and secure communication.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple could pull iCloud from the UK</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/" />
    <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/apple-could-pull-icloud-from-the-uk/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 9, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I know many of you who read my posts are in the U.K. You may have already read this. Quoting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2025/02/07/could-apple-pull-icloud-services-from-uk/&quot;&gt;Tim Hardwick, MacRumors&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“A more dramatic response from Apple would involve completely removing iCloud services from the UK. While this would protect Apple&#39;s encryption standards, it would severely disrupt millions of UK users who rely on iCloud for photo storage, device backups, and document syncing. Users would need to find alternative cloud storage solutions and potentially lose access to years of accumulated data.”&lt;/em&gt; Are you concerned about this possibility?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cracked Corn 🌽</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/" />
    <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/cracked-corn/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 10, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.snap.as/QVy072ds.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeding time around here is no joke! We go through 100 pounds of cracked corn every week to keep the deer and wild turkeys happy as they wander our 10-acre property. Our place is actually a Certified Wildlife Habitat with the state of New Jersey, and we love all the creatures that call it home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we go through 40 pounds of birdseed for all the birds. Of course, the raccoon has figured out a little trick—every night, it climbs the tree, hangs off the bird feeder, and dumps the seed just so it can feast. Smart little guy! I haven’t spotted the groundhog yet this year, but I’m sure it’ll make an appearance soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On - Which HTML element are you [Quiz]?</title>
    <link href="https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://ldstephens.me/posts/on-which-html-element-are-you-quiz/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Posted on February 13, 2025 by Loren&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James at James’ Coffee Blog created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/02/13/html-quiz&quot;&gt;fun quiz&lt;/a&gt; called “Which HTML element are you?” It has ten questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the quiz and “I’m the &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; element! You’re great at gathering ideas from different sources and putting them together”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>